Although each of the world's countries would like to dispute this fact,
14൭൭൧ ൧൧൧ ടല്ട്യാ ഗ്റടട ൨ വ്൧ല൭ നന്നാലു ൧7൭൪ ൧...
we French know the truth:
൭൩ 0൧൬ ഥ്ലഥലട 49007 (ക്ഥാഥലഥഥക്‌
The best food in the world is made in France.
ഒകെ 4൦ ഥ്‌ വ്ഥ൭ റ്ഥഥ൭! ന്‌ ഥലദഥല്‌ട
The best food in France is made in Paris.
൧ സന ഖക്ഗണെ 4൦ ധ്‌ ഥ്ലഥധല്ട ല്ഡ്ഥദ! വ്‌ ഥഒഥട
And the best food in Paris, some say, is made by Chef Auguste Gusteau.
റെ (൭൭ 0൭, വ്‌ 7ഒട൭% ഥ്‌൦ ഗ൭ഥറ ൯൩൭5൭ ള്‍ഥ്റഥട൭ ഥേട4ഒ൭൧7
Gusteau's restaurant is the toast of Paris,
ടെ0൭൨ ൭൧5൭൭൧ 9റ൭4൭7 10 4ല൧൭ വ്‌ ൧ഒ7൭..
booked five months in advance.
.. വാഗ 5 ൧ഥ൭ഥ (൧൧0 ഒഗഒ
And his dazzling ascent to the top of fine French cuisine
൧൭൦ :ഒറുലനഥറ്ഥഥുഒ നഗെഥറക്‌ 0൭7.
has made his competitors envious.
.നണന്നാഥക്ഥ ടറഗ ലേന്ഥാഥ്ഥ
He is the youngest chef ever to achieve a five-star rating.
൧9 ഒറ്ഒ൭ 4ധ്ഥറ നട്ട )ഴ ലന 4ഖലഗനട റലഒ7ഒഥ 5 ൧൧01൭൧
Chef Gusteau's cookbook, Anyone Can Cook!
ലടില്വാല്യധന 80൨൧൧൧0൭൧൭
climbed to the top of the bestseller list.
ലടില്വാല്യധന 8ംിലവ്്ലനടട്റ
But not everyone celebrates its success.
7ല്‌ക്ഥ! 77റ൭% ലട 0 നലക ഷൃ
Amusing title, Anyone Can Cook!
7 ഖലു നെറ്റു 70൭, ലടില്വാല്യധന 8ംിലവ്്ലനടട്റ
Anton Ego - FOOD CRITIC "THE GRIM EATER"
൧൯൦0 റം - ലലപലഗ്വ്ധിച്ധ്പച്പ ല്ല്ച്്വ്പ പ്ല”
What's even more amusing is that Gusteau actually seems to believe it.
൧൪൧൭ )൬ (൧൧ നെറ്റു ഗദ ദെ 5൧െ7൭7-ഠ൭. നന്നാലു
!, on the other hand, take cooking seriously.
൭൭൭, ൧൭റ൮൭൧നഒറമദ്ഥഥ, നഴെറ്റടസ27 ടല 0൧൭5൭ 7 ഒടദര്ഥ
And, no, I don't think anyone can do it.
൧൭൧, ഒ ടഒ൭ 4ഒ നഗ ട്ട[ഒഥദ 20൭7 7ലഒ൭ഡ്ഷഥ)൭
This is me.
൧൨ ഒ.
think it's apparent ! need to rethink my life a little bit.
൧൮ 7ഒട൭ ൭൭൭൭ ഒ൨൧ (൭ഥട ൧ഗ്സ്ഗ്‌ ട്ലനഥ്‌ട 40 7൧ ഒ
What's my problem?
൧൪൧൭9 795ഒ4൭ ഒ൧൨7
First of all, I'm a rat.
൧ല്ലനട ടല്ഷ്ഷ്‌, ഒധ ടലല്യ ധധട
Which means life is hard.
൮ ഥലന്നഖഗട 7റ൧ ഒറ വേഷ
And second, I have a highly developed sense of taste and smell.
൧൭൧ :൫൨൧൭, ഒ:൧ നലന്വാഥ)൭! റ്൦൭ 7൭.5൭ റ 2൭൧ )൭ റ്‌
Flour, eggs, sugar, vanilla bean...
ലാന, ലഥ, റി, 0 ബി.
Oh! Small twist of lemon.
॥ ാലമന൫1൦ണ൦൩..
Whoa, you can smell all that? You have a gift.
1009, !9്ധ ാഠ16വാദ്ധ ടഠനസ്ധ വധ? ദ്്ധലാനാല്യ
This is Emile, my brother. He's easily impressed.
൧ ൧൩൭, ഒററ ഒ. ൧9 770709 വ്രറുഗ്സക്ഥ
So you can smell ingredients? So what?
ദ്ധ ൦1൩3൨ ധേന സ്വന്‌? പ്ഒഠി..!
This is my dad. He's never impressed.
൧ ഒഷ്ഥ ഒ൭:൧. ൧9 4ഒലാലനകഗ (ഭറുഗ്ണ
He also happens to be the leader of our clan.
൧9 ഒറ്ല൭ (൭൧൭ ഭഗ്ന ൭
So, what's wrong with having highly developed senses?
പ്ഒവ്‌, ഒ൧൭ ടഒ൭൧)൭ നണ്ൊാഥഷ്‌ റ്ഒ൦്ട 9 2൧൭൧൨
-Whoa, whoa, whoa! Don't eat that! -What's going on here?
പ൩ നല ്ധ! - ക്യാ ൮൬൭ ടട ലാലില്വബല്‌?
Turns out that funny smell was rat poison.
ഥാ൭-7ഥഥെ൭ ൧2ഒഥ ൧ലഥ്ഥ്ഥ ഒറ൭4൭7 7ഒഗഥറ ൭5
Suddenly, Dad didn't think my talent was useless.
72൭9-൧9 ഒഷ്ഗ 4൭:ല൭ട൭ 2൭4൭॥ ഒ ൭:ഥാലറുഗട
! was feeling pretty good about my gift,
൧൮ 7ഒടട ഒറു൭: ൧൭7 ടട! ൧൭൭! ഒ
until Dad gave me a job.
൧൧90൭7 ഒക ഥലസ്ക്ഥ ഒ൨ ടദഡ ഷഒ
Clean.
ലട.
That's right. Poison checker.
൪ 2ഖ്ഥ്‌.. നനലസ് ഗ്ഗ
Cleanerino.
നാമ്ലാലടിന..
Close to godliness.
വ ൬൦ ഭട॥ന൫൨..
Which means clean. You know, cleanliness is close to...
വാവാന്നദ്ഭ്ധഠ ാ൦ടി0.. ദ്ധ 1ദഡ, ഭ്വാലടിനഡ ലന്പ ന...
Never mind. Move on.
1 ല്വാമില.. 1 ബടിത്ല്‍്‌
Well, it made my dad proud.
7൭ ഗ7ലനാ൭കഥ ഒഷ്ഥ ഒ൭:൧ ഥാഥെറ്ററട
Now, don't you feel better, Remy? You've helped a noble cause.
ടന, 1ഠ90ഷ്നിത്ധ ടഃ ലാലി സെ
Noble? We're thieves, Dad.
ല്ലി" ൭ 39150 ലി, മുര
And what we're stealing is, let's face it, garbage.
൧൭0 ദവാ ൮൬ ൩൩ ലോ ലിം, നഹൃദ്വ ടയ, ടന്വാമ൨..
It isn't stealing if no one wants it.
1ാധിര്സര നലഥഥ വിര ദ്ട്ദ ടരല്വദ ന്ധി
If no one wants it, why are we stealing it?
പിര ഒഠ്9 ട്വ നദ്ഡിയ്സുയ, നല്വാമ ന്മ നഹ്സ്‌?!
Let's just say we have different points of view.
്ക്ഥ ട൭ഒ (൭൩ നണ്റാഥ്വഷ്‌ ഗററ്റ്റടറ ) ൧2
This much I knew:
൮ ഒ ൭ഥഥ
If you are what you eat, then I only want to eat the good stuff.
പ്ര (കഥ ഒ൭ഠ്൭ഒ൦ ഒ) (൭൧ ന൭൪൧..
But to my dad...
7ഒഥ൧ ൧ാടറ്ട9 ഒ൭൧ ഒഡ൦
Food is fuel.
1-111-14
You get picky about what you put in the tank, your engine is going to die.
പിതര്ധ ലേദധല്‍ മ ഖ്യാ൮യ ത്വ ൭ ിന ൭10, ബ്്ബത്ധ ല്ത്ഥ നമി.
Now shut up and eat your garbage.
നാ ഠിദണ ൦ നലിത്ഥ ട്വ ത്ധ
Look, if we're going to be thieves,
പിര റ്൭ നലിലദഠി 00ഥ..
why not steal the good stuff in the kitchen,
ഭലല്വാ 1൭0 നി നലിത്നന ലിം ഠി ഠിന ഠ്ല്രധ...
where nothing is poisoned?
1:11: 1:11:
First of all, we are not thieves.
ലെന ടലരി॥।, 11വാധിത്ന ലാലല
Secondly, stay out of the kitchen and away from the humans.
1:11: 1118 ചവി ഠി്വാധ ഠ്‌ നധ്ധടിദ
It's dangerous.
1ബരലാനോദ്മുര
! know I'm supposed to hate humans, but there's something about them.
൧൮ ഗെ ൭:ഥ ലോല ഗലസ്ഥാലല്‌ ന ഗലട്‌ഒ,
They don't just survive. They discover, they create.
07ഥഥതക്ഥ ലര ഗ൭(ലകര! 77റ൧൧,
! mean, just look at what they do with food.
77ഒ൭൧൨൧, !ററഠഗ൦ ൧൭൮൬ നഗ 2൧൧൧൭! റ്റ്ഗ നദര്ഥടഥ
How can! describe it?
289റ9നഒറദഒ ഹ ഒ:ധലഒടരഥഥൃഒ?
Good food is like music you can taste, color you can smell,
ഒകെ 9 ്ട്ഥ നടന നഥമ% 9 :൭൧ ൧൧൭൦7 7൭൭൭,
There is excellence all around you.
൧ീറ്9 (കറഥാദ!ഒ ന്‌ ടല ഒറഠ്ദ
You need only be aware to stop and savor it.
൧ഗറ്ദഒ ഗഥ്നേദ ഹല്ല ട6റ്൭ റ നഗെഗദൃക
Oh, Gusteau was right.
റ, ൨54൭൭ ഥല്ഥ്‌
Oh, amazing.
൨൧, നെറ്റു...
Each flavor was totally unique.
കല[ഒ൧ ൧ലടഒടഒ നലനദെറ്റ ഗഗ
But combine one flavor with another,
7ഒ൧! ൧൧ന്‌ ടദധവാലടടട റ്റ്ഗന ൧ലഒടഒ (൭൨..
and something new was created.
.. റ ടട്േഥദ്ഥു ഗാഡ ല്‌ വ്‌ ല്ഥ്൭
So now I had a secret life.
പ്ഒധ്‌ ഗ്ഗ ഒ സനലന്ഥഥഷ ഥേദഥ 7൭൧54൭ ഗ്ന (കഒവവഥെ
The only one who knew about it was Emile.
൭൭1൧-5൭) ൭൮)൭ (൭൧൧ നാറ്റ) ഒ൭ഒ7 ൧൩൭
l found a mushroom.
൧൮ ഠ്ദ്വൃഥന്ാട ട്വ ഘ്ന
Come on, you're good at hiding food. Help me find a good place to put this.
ദ്ധ 04 ട൦0010൫൭0 നമ൭൫൭൨൩. ദ്ധ മിവ ലോ ന്വാമ ധ്ലല്ലിറമ്ല ബ്‌
He doesn't understand me, but l can be myself around him.
൧ഒ9 ഒ നലനഒഒനസ്‌ ഒഡ. 4൭07 ഒ 20൭ (ഒ൨്‌ വസ്ഥ ടഹെഠ്ഥ്‌ ന്‌ ട്ഥാഥന്നുട
Why are you walking like that?
(ദറ്വാധ്ധ ലല നന ധ്‌?
I don't want to constantly have to wash my paws.
൧ിവ 1൭0 ന്സ ഇനലിഭാടടധി നാദ ടവ ടലല്ധ
Did you ever think about how we walk on the same paws
ലെന ന്ിലാദാല്നടന്മ ന ലാലുമിദല..
that we handle food with?
11110111 റ്റാ നദി?
You ever think about what we put into our mouths?
ദ്ധ ഥീ യാ വാവ ന്മ നടി ഭ ഠിന ന്ധ്ഥന്മ?
All the time.
ലോപ നട.
When I eat, I don't want to taste everywhere my paws have been.
8॥9 മിവ നമിയ്ഥ, ലവ ടി൦നല്ഡ ടട ഠി നന ല്ലി മ്വലാലഠ്ഃ
Well, go ahead.
1ലബടിത്ഥ ടല.
But if Dad sees you walking like that, he's not going to like it.
വല്യ ദരി നന്പാല്ലത്ധ ലാലു ല്റ്ധ, ഠിദ 100 നനസ്ൂയിവുര
What have you got there?
യായ ത്വ ദ ഠി ട്ട?
You found cheese?
ദ്ര്ധ്ധന്വാദഭ്വ്?
And not just any cheese. Tomme de chévre de pays!
ബാധിത ടലാാഭ്വ്ധ. ഗ്നട ഠീ ഗഗ ഠ% ഉദ്യഭ!
That would go beautifully with my mushroom.
൮ ടു ടറി ഠിുലാധനാത്ഥ ന ലേഡിയോഥ മിവ
And...
൧0..
This rosemary! This rosemary
ടന ബി! ദംടനമങ ബ്‌ 9൩..
with maybe with a few drops from this sweet grass.
.സ്൨വനാന്വാലാലഭ്വാദ 01 ടല നി റടട ബബ
Well, throw it on the pile, l guess, and then we'll... You know...
മേന്മ ൪൭ 95 വമ്പാധന്ന വധ,
We don't want to throw this in with the garbage. This is special.
൭ നല ന്വാല്ല്ബിഭ ദീന ട്വ. ബ ഠ്ലില്വ്ടിനടമ
But we're supposed to return to the colony
ലവ 09 ടലാദ്ധസര ഭമ്പാഃ!। ൫ രിബ്‌
before sundown or, you know, Dad's gonna...
ടലാല്ധന നമ്മിഘി നന്ന ദ്ധ ദുര ല്ത്ഥ--
There are possibilities unexplored here.
൧ഠ9 സ്ധ്ിന്ന്൩ന൭ ാല്ധന ഠ1ടില്യ1൨ ിട്ബി
We got to cook this.
ധ൭1൭൬൫൭ നടടമിറ്ല്‍്‌
Now, exactly how we cook this is the real...
നാ ാാല്നമന്മ ന്മ നല നനടടല്ല്ലി 150 ടഠദട0 ടലാല--
The key is to keep turning it.
ധ്യ മില ധിറനടബട നന്നാ ല॥റ്സ൭
Get the smoky flavor nice and even.
ഉല്യാബിത്ഥ ടാ ട്വ ടല
That storm's getting closer.
്വാധ ഠ്ട൨ ടനണടിന്ന ലയ
Hey, Remy, you think that maybe we shouldn't be so...
ലസ, നസ്ധനാന്നിന്മ ദവാഡധ്ധാടേഠ്ട ടാ
You got to taste this!
ദ്ധ നടട॥ മട ബി
This is... It's got this kind of... It's burny, melty...
ബി-- 5 നന്തി ടട മടദ-- 1ലലാദിഷ്വ, ദി
It's not really a smoky taste. It's a certain... It's kind of like a...
1ാധിത്ബില്ലാനലാന്മലെ മട മടല്വാ. [ബസ ൮3510-- ഒ ടല്രാല--
It's got, like, this "ba-boom, zap" kind of taste. Don't you think?
1൭ നലസ്വാധസഭി, ഒട നേന "9- ൧ഠഠന, മല്യ". 1ടഠവ്വത്ധ മട ലാല്ഡ?
-What would you call that flavor? -Lightning-y?
൧്വാ മിര നന്ദിത ാടദ വധ? - ധി?
Yeah. It's lightning-y! We got to do that again.
൭. 1ധിട ഗന്ധ ടര
Okay, when the next storm comes, we'll go up on the roof...
ളി ലാധ്യു ടട ഠ്ക്ദ്ു, ന മിത നലിലഭ ധ്സാഥ്--
I know what this needs. Saffron. A little saffron would make this.
൧ിവ ദസ ലാവ ബി ാലിധിത്ന. 50.
Saffron. Why do I get the feeling
൭9100. (ന്്വാട 1൮ 90 മടലിത൨..
-it's in the kitchen? -It's in the kitchen.
9 0 ദിന ഠ്ല്ാധ?
-Saffron. -Not good.
- [ദിവാലി
Don't like it. She's going to wake up.
1 ടധി൭. ൧1൭ ിവ്ഥ ലു
I've been down here a million times.
൧ിവ ഠ്ദ്വ്യാനണ്മ ഭാമ ടബ്‌ ടലഥ്ദ ര
She turns on the cooking channel, boom, she never wakes up.
൧9 ദടന്റ ടല്ധമ്ന നനടടമ്ലാംഠന, [1:11 11-51-11:
You've been here a million times?
ദ്ധ ലാലന്മനഭ ടബ്‌ ടല ര?
I'm telling you, saffron will be just the thing. Gusteau swears by it.
൧ിവ ലാട, ട്ട ട്നോയ്വാസുയ. വ്ട്ലാധ ബസരിറുധന്ല്ഖ്സു
Okay. Who's Gusteau?
വം ടിച്വാദ വവട്ടദ്ധ?
Just the greatest chef in the world. Wrote this cookbook.
ബില ടം ്ധിഖ് ന്ടട ലാലി രബ. "നാ നന്ഡിട ധ്വനി
Wait. You read?
പൂം. ദ്ധ നന്നാ?
-Well, not excessively. -Oh, man. Does Dad know?
1ലിഠില്വാലിലാ1സില്ാിന്ഥ ടാ - ൧ഠ൭1൭൨ മുര ല്ഡ?
You could fill a book, a lot of books, with things Dad doesn't know.
സ്വത 001൦0 ഠ്0ാലല്ചി ില്വത്ധ..
And they have, which is why I read. Which is also our secret.
൧0൫ നനാ 0൩, ൮ ലാലാ വ നല്പാദഠേ നാ ലിം ടിന
I don't like secrets.
11110111:
All this cooking and reading and TV-watching
ല്ധട ബ്‌ നനടടമി് നലമ്പാടടേ ഒര ൬൦൫൧0൯൦0 ൦.
while we read and cook.
ദ്വി ന നല്പാദദേ ൭0 നടനടട3।
It's like you're involving me in crime, and I let you.
1൭ ട൦ഠില്വത്ധ നല്[ാഖിത്ഥ ലിവ ദിന ന്മ, ദ മിവ ിലിത്ത്ഖ
Why do I let you?
(൭റല്വാ മിവ ിലലത്ഥത്ധ?
What's taking those kids so long?
൧്യാ ൮൬൭ നസഭ്വാലാതാധഠ്ല്റലാധാലയഡ നണട ടന്ന
L'Aquila saffron. Italian. Huh?
൭൩൦0൨ ൧മറ്ധിമ, 191. ലന?
Gusteau says it's excellent. Good thing the old lady is a food love...
വ്വട്ടാ്ധ യ്യ ടാ ടടഠ്ല്വാ
Forget mystique. This is about your cooking.
2൧൭(൫൭൧ 757 ൧ ഒറ്ഒ(൭7 ന൦െറ്ററെട! ഗന ട9ടഒഷ്ഥ ഒററഠ്൭
Hey! That's Gusteau. Emile, look.
ധി വട്ട്ധ. മില, ॥൩1
Great cooking is not for the faint of heart.
ഴലനടടഒ റ്റ്ഗ ൧൭ ഥഥഥഒഗ ശെ 9 ൧റെശ്‌
You must be imaginative, strong hearted.
൧ഗറ്ദ നടെ ഒ൨്‌ നറ്റ്‌, 4൧൭ ടനനകററ്റല്‌
You must try things that may not work.
൧ഗറ്ഒ 7950 ഥോ ഥല്ഷ ൭ നഥന്്ഗ 1൭4ഥാലഗടഒ7്‌
And you must not let anyone define your limits
൧൭൧ 9൦ ൧൭൧കഥ ടട്ടഒ്ഥദ നല്ല്ഒഗ്ക്ഥ ൧൭9 (ഗഠ്‌ ഒററ്ഒ..
because of where you come from.
..4ഭഥട ൭൭൭൧5൧ ഒററ
Your only limit is your soul.
൧൭ഠ്‌ ഒറഠ്ദ ഒഠ്൭'ഒ7 ൧൭ ഒറ്‌
What I say is true. Anyone can cook, But only the fearless can be great.
൧൪൧9) 5൭൭ ദെര്വാക്ഥ ഒറ്ഒ൭ ൧2ല൨0൭
Pure poetry.
ല്വട। ടലി
But it was not to last.
7ഒ൧ (9 ഗ൧ാഥഥ'ഒഗ ൧ ലെന
Gusteau's restaurant lost one of its five stars
ടെ0൭൨ ൭൦൧549൭൧ (കഗ7൦റ്റണെ 5൭4൭൧ ഒല വ്ഥറ്‌ 2 2൧01൧൮൦൭...
after a scathing review by France's top food critic, Anton Ego.
..ട്ലല്ാടട ഒട ഒറ 7റ൭ ദ്ധ ഥലാ ൧൦റഗ്ഥനടക്ഥടെ 4ഖലകഥട! £ല്ഥധ്ട,
It was a severe blow to Gusteau,
79൭ ഒഠ്ദ൭'ഒഗ ടഒഡ ഒന്ഥാലഥ ഗലാ ഗഠ്‌ 6ഥ51൫8൧..
and the brokenhearted chef died shortly afterwards,
.. റ 4ധര്ഥറ നടു ഭഗ 7ഥ ന൭൧ 4ഒലഒനട (൭൩൧൨൪൭൧..
which, according to tradition, meant the loss of another star.
1൭൧൮, നലഥഡഥ്‌ 79൨൭൦, ൧ാലനനഖഗട (കഥഥറെറുറെ 594൧ 9൮ ൧൧1൭൧൮
Gusteau is dead?
വ്വട്ടദ്ധ 0 നബ?
Run!
ല്‌!
No, you'll lead her to the colony!
11റ്മധ്ധ മത്വാ ഠി ഭ വംലി്‌!
-Help, Remy, help! -Emile! Start swinging the light!
101൦൩൮, സു, 0൦! - കൃവബ്ത്ഥിന്വധഡധ
Try to grab you.
1൭൫ ലോ ഡോയ്വാത്ധ
Emile, swing to me.
സില, ദവിത്നിന ദ്വ
Evacuate! Everyone, to the boats.
ദാനാ! ട്ധഃ ൦0, ൫ 0൦
-Let me through! -The book.
ദലലിത്ഥ മിവല്ധ! ക
Excuse me. Move, move.
ഗിചിര്ഥ മവ. പച്ബയല്ടല്‍്‌
Go, go, go, go. Move, move, move.
ട്ടി, [515൩,൮൭15൩. ലാ, ലോ, ലോ
Get the bridge up! Move it, move it!
ചിറ ബമ്പാബ് യ! ലാഖ്‌, ലോദി
Hey, Johnny! Hurry!
പഠന ലാബ്‌
Push off. Come on.
10151 ല്രോ
Get hold!
ലവി!
-Take the baby. Here! -Give me your paw.
എസ്ഡി വാകി ബ്‌. ല്‍ - ഒലലിത്ഥ മിവ ല്വാല്ലിതിറത്ധ
Hey, wait for me!
ലല, ഡന്ാധ മഡ്‌
Is everybody here? Do we have everybody?
ലന്ധട ൦ 39 ഠി ടബ്‌? ലന്ധട ൦09 ൭൨3?
-Wait a minute. Where's Remy? -Right here. I'm coming.
ഗന സ്റ - ൧ ട്‌. ഷ്വ ഖ്ണോ
I'm coming!
൧ിവ ഠ്യ!
Hold on, Son. Give him something to grab on to.
ധന്ാല, നലം ദലലിത്ഥ 19 ടട ധി
Come on, boy. Paddle, Son.
൧൮൪. ചവന, ന
Come on. Reach for it.
ല്വോമ! ഒ
You can do it.
ദ്ധ ൦1൦൩ പവിര്സു൭
-Remy! -Dad!
ലസി - ക്ര
Come on. You can make it. You can make it.
൧൮0. ദ്ധാംില്‍്വി്ല്ഡ്യ്സുര. ദ്ധ ൦1൦൩ പവിര്സു൭
Guys, wait. Stop!
പം൩. ഒല!
Hold on! Wait for me. Hold on.
പസ! സഥാാല ലിവ. പസ
Dad?
ഷുഖ്്ന
Which way?
൧൧൭0 നന്മ?
! waited
൧൮ നദഥറ്ററഥ..
for a sound,
ഒല ൧൧൧൪..
. a voice,
.. ഒ ടഥ൭7൭..
a sign,
.. ഒ !ഒഥറ്ഒ..
something.
..ടെഥദ്ഥ
If you are hungry, go up and look around, Remy.
പിതത്ധല്വാല, നലിലിഭ മട ൭0 ൫൭5 ടല, "ന്ന
Why do you wait and mope?
(ദറല്വാധ്ധ സാല ്ബലാന്ധടണ്‌?
Well, I've just lost my family, all my friends,
ചവ ലാല ടല്യ ശ്വാന ശ്ധുല്വ, ടലന്ധദ മഗിത്യബ്വ..
probably forever.
സ്ഥാന ധം ടി ണു
-How do you know? -Well, I...
റ്റാ ധ്ധല്ഡ? - ൧൮...
You are an illustration. Why am I talking to you?
ദ്ധ 301൭൨ ടാഡ ്ധട്ടടി. (൭റ്വാ മിവ ല്ിത്വാ ഠ്ബത്ധ?
Well, you just lost your family, all your friends. You are lonely.
ദ്്ധവാബ ടല്യരഭ്വ്ാന ദ്ധ ത്വ, ടസ്ധാം യധാനതമത്ഖ
Yeah. Well, you're dead.
൭. ദ്ധ മനി
Ah, but that is no match for wishful thinking.
൧൨, ട്വ ധവാധിത്ബ്ല നദ്ദ [11-11 1:1ി
If you focus on what you've left behind,
പിതത്വ 1ഠവട ദ്വാ൮൬൭ ഠ്ട്നിലാടട,
you'll never be able to see what lies ahead.
ധ്ധ 1 0111 ലായ ലാല ഠി ന്മഠ്ല്യാന
Now go up and look around.
നാ ന്ലിംല്ടെ 500൫2 ടല്‍ശഭ॥ന
What are you doing?
യായ ത്ധവാധമ്ല്‌?
I'm hungry.
ത:
I don't know where I am,
ചവ ട്ിറവല്ഡ ലവ ഠി ന്ന,
and I don't know when I'll find food again.
൦ മിവ ലി്വല്ഡ 019 മിവ ലിഖബ്ധന്ധാദ ന്ത!
Remy, you are better than that. You are a cook.
ലസുപത്ധില്ിവാലി ഇ ദ്ധ ടട ്ധിഖ് നടട
A cook makes. A thief takes. You are not a thief.
ധിയാ നടടമിനനടടമ ലാലി നലന്ധാ॥. ദ്ധവാധിത്ല ഥി
But lam hungry.
വല്യ മ്വല്വാല
Food will come, Remy.
ഗിലിരനാ൨ ലിത്ഥ ഠാ, സ്പ
Food always comes to those who love to cook.
ഗിലി൭നാ൨ ലിത്ഥ ഠാ നഠ ന്ഥി൮൭ ട്ധിര നനമട%
-You think lam playing? -You don't have the guts.
ദ്ധ ൫൭൭ ലിവ നനന, ഥംിട? - ദ്ധ 1ദറമ്ാലമ്ബി
Paris?
[1
All this time I've been underneath Paris?
ലന ബി മിവ ലാട ഠി രായ ലലിട?
It's beautiful.
േസിസമ
The most beautiful.
ലിനാ ടേസിം
Gusteau's? Your restaurant?
ദ്വട്ടദ്ധ? ദ൦ട്ംത്ധ?
You've led me to your restaurant.
ധാ ടവ ഭര ടട്ഠലിത്ധ
It seems as though I have. Yes. There it is. l have led you to it.
൭൭൦0॥150൩-൦1൭10 നന ൮൭. "ഒ
I got to see this.
ചവ ഭന്മ 0൫2ബി
-Ready to go on table seven. -Coming around.
ദലടലഠിദ ധിനലദ വ്ധ്്ധിറ - ദ്ധ ലാട ണന ടിട്
I need more soup bowls, please.
ചവ ലാല്ധിത്ിലാാബുതി നാവി ട്വ
I need two rack of lamb. I need more leeks.
൧ിവ ാല്ധിത്ന 2 000 ഒന 110. ചവ ാല്ധിത്ിലാസാബഭ്ലിട
I need two salmon, three salade composée, and three filet.
ചവ ാല്ധിത്ഥ 2 ടനം, 3 ടലി ഗഥേന്ഥാടം, ൭0൫3 ല്‍
Three orders of salade composée working.
3 ാടാനമറ ടട ഗേന്വാഠടം ടലഠിബാ ഠിധമ
Firing two orders, seared salmon.
ഗ്ധിം നനനടടമ 2 ലാട ടല്നംബാലിത്വ
Don't mess with my mise!
പു൩ിര്വേ ലട മിഡ്‌
Open down low.
ധിയാ ലമ - കവ ലിധിത്ഥ 0 ധിഗനല്ട 4
I'm getting buried here.
൧ിവ ൭൨ ഘയാല്ടന ഠിട്ല്‍
Hello, Chef Skinner. How your night be now?
ല്ലം, ഡി നടടചം പന്നല. റ്റി ദ്ദ നടിദത്ധിന്പ്‌?
-Evening, chef. -Ordering deux filet.
ലഹു, ഡി നട -[ഗീലനടടറ 2 ല്‍
Hey, boss, look who is here.
8ഠട, ൫5 ടില്വാ ഠി ടിബി
Alfredo Linguini, Renata's little boy.
ചാം നധ്ബ, മല്ഗന്മ്മ
-Hi. -All grown up, eh?
ഠി ഠിഠഡട, 07
You remember Renata, Gusteau's old flame?
ദ്ധ ന ന്മ, ഷരടിനിനമ ഡട്ട്ധ?
-Yes. How are you... -Linguini.
൧൮൭൫൭. ൧൭ ന്ല്വാലത്ധ? - ധ്‌
Yes, Linguini. So nice of you to visit. How is...
വം ധ്ബ ലിസ ത്ധ മ നലിയ. 8ദ്ന്മന൭..
-My mother? -Renata.
2 മിവ? - ലമ
-Yes, Renata. How is she? -Good.
൭, ന്മ. 8ാലനടന്മ ഭദഠ്ദ്സര്‌? - ഒലി
Well, not... She's been better. 1 mean...
1ഒധലി-- ൧ ഗണട്നിലാ!ന ലിം [ഗിലിദ്ധാ।വ..
She died.
8:1൦ 1:11111:11
Oh, don't be. She believed in heaven, so she's covered.
ധ്പ്യാനാാലടന്വഖ്‌. ൧൭ ലാലേ ഠി ഡു, ഒഠ। ഠിദ ലല ന്ഥ!
You know, afterlife-wise?
ദ്ധ ലസ, ഠ്‌ ടാ വ്യാ ടലില്ാട നബ?
-What's this? -She left it for you.
യാല്‌? - ൧ വനാമി ധ്ലത്ധ
Il think she hoped it would help me,
ചവ ടട ഠി ലാലലാ ലിഖ്വ സ്വ മിവ.
you know, get a job here.
ചിരവ ലിസ, ചാമ ഭ്ലദ ഠി ട്ബ
But of course. Gusteau wouldn't hesitate.
ലവ ടവഠിടറ ന്ധ. ദ്ട്ലാധ മിന ലാലാ
Any son of Renata's is more than...
ഗിനാ-നാന്മ ലി രന്മ്ട ലാ നഠ--
Yes, well, we could file this and if something suitable opens up...
ധ്്വാഠില്വടിത്ഥ ബി ടിയ ദ ട്ട ൮൬ ലാടം
We have already hired him.
ദ്വി ൭0 ലാഥ0 ബാ ഠിദ ലാല്ല
What? How dare you hire someone without my...
യാമ! ഒലി യവ മ്പാ॥ ടടടടംു ലഭ) ലാ ഘ്വാലന്ലമ്ബ്വ--
We needed a garbage boy.
ഗമ ാലിധിത്ബാധഠ്ട്‌ ഘായ' ടന്വാമവ
Oh, garbage. Well...
൭൨, ട്വ.
I'm glad it worked out.
൧൮ റന്പാട ബസ൭ 511 ടലടടമി
I can't believe it.
൧ിവ 150 നന്പാലമുയസമ
A real gourmet kitchen, and I get to watch.
ലോധ ദ്ല്ാധഠധന്നല്‍ ടലാല്ല, 0 ടവ ഠ്വ നല്‍
You've read my book. Let us see how much you know, huh?
ദ്ധ ഠ്ദ്വാടഠേ 0ധിവ വ. വീ 5 ലദ്വാദ ലാബി ധ്ധല്ഡ, ന
Which one is the chef?
നാ നട്ട ടബ ന്ധര്നാ നടടല്റ
-Oh, that guy. -Very good.
പല്ല - ്റു്ധാടാട
Who is next in command?
കല്യാ !ര്ധം ഭാധദ്‌?
The sous chef. There.
ധിയാ നടി ടംഖട. ൧ ടന
The sous is responsible for the kitchen when the chef's not around.
ധിയാ നടി ടംഖട ല്മഡ്യാഥനയയലാോ ന്മ ഠ്ല്ാധ..
Saucier, in charge of sauces. Very important.
ടദ്ധഠില്‌,ാല്ാഥനഘൃദ്ലാ മടി ടഠട. നാമ്‌ ലാസ്നാ
Chef de partie, demi chef de partie, both important.
ലല്‌ റ ഹാനി, ഠിടബി ല്‌ ടല ലാല്ല, രാധ ലാസ്നാ
Commis, commis, they're cooks. Very important.
ഠംന്മ്പട, ഗേസ്സ്ട, നട6യ 20991210 ധി നടടചം നാട്‌ ലാസ്നാ
You are a clever rat. Now, who is that?
ദ്ധ നിവട ൮൭ ടലിത്ു, ട്ല്വാ ധ്‌?
Oh, him? He's nobody.
൭൨, ഠിദ? 8ധിത്ഥ ടടടല്വാ
Not nobody. He is part of the kitchen.
ദധി ാധിത്ഥ ടടടില്വാട. ൧൭ ടലാദനമ്ിന ഇ മന ഠ്ല്ാധ്‌
No, he's a plongeur or something.
1൭ ഠി ടന ്ധ്ത്നാ ഒട 01099൩ ദ്വ ടടട്ധദ്ധ
He washes dishes or takes out the garbage. He doesn't cook.
ഉട നല്പാദടധന ൧0൩9൭൩ ദ്ധ ശ്വ ടണ്വാമ൨. ൧൭ പ നണട
-But he could. -Uh, no.
ലവ ഠിദലാഠില
How do you know? What do I always say?
റ്റാ ധ്ധല്ഡ? ൧൮൬ 3൮ ടലല്ധ ത?
Anyone can cook.
ഭലടില്വാാധാഠില്‍ നണട
Well, yeah, anyone can. That doesn't mean that anyone should.
൭, ടടില്വാ ാധാഠില്‍. ൮ 1മിവാല്നലിന്മ ടടടിദ്വാദ ലാ ാമ്ധ
Well, that is not stopping him. See?
൮ 1൦നാടസിത്ഥ ഠിദ. നബാം
What is he doing? No. No! No, this is terrible!
൧്വാ൮൬ ഠി ടടഠ്യാാധ്? 1191. നില നിഠ്ല്ല്ലി ലഡിറ
He's ruining the soup. And nobody's noticing?
ഉട നലാടദലിറക്ഥ ടഥ്വാധ. ൦ ൪൭ഠി൭ ട്വ ലലടടന?
It's your restaurant. Do something.
ബി ടട ത്വ. ധിം ടട
What can I do? lam a figment of your imagination.
൧്വാ൮൬ 0ഠ01ല൨ മ്വാധമ്‌. എവ ബഭ്ല്വന്മരി്ംനടാമ്മടി ത്വ
But he's ruining the soup! We got to tell someone that he's...
1ല്വാ। റിദ നലാടലിറമ്ല ഥോ വധ! ധ51൭൫൭ ൧ലന്ല്ഡ ടടടടംമ ൬ ഠ1--
Table five coming up, right now.
ഴിലദ ന 90 ടിലാ, ടയ
-Coming down the line. -Set.
നാ ദ ടയ
Hot! Open oven!
ദ്ട! 8ധിര ക്ധല
Oui, chef. One filet mignon, three lamb, two duck.
വ, ധിരന നടി നിസി, 3 ന 0,
Fire those soufflés for table six, ja.
ഗിടാ1 ടംഥിടഡ ധി൦നലട 6, ൮൭
-Five minutes, chef. -Oh, God.
ലന സ്വ ധിരത്ഥാ നട - ൭൨, ഡി
Tonight, I'd like to present the foie gras.
[ടിന [ബ, ടവ നലലാലടമ്പാട്വത്ഥ്ഠംട റലടട
It has a wonderful finish.
1൭ നലസ്വാധസഖി ടവ ലാട
Ready to go on table seven. Come on! Let's go!
ദലടലഠിദ ലിലി നലദ 7. ലാഖ്‌! ഗി ലാല!!
Remy! What are you waiting for?
ലസ ല്യാ൮യ ത്വ ഡഘാധില!?
Is this going to become a regular thing with you?
൧ഠിട്യ് ബി ഖ്യു ലാിത്ധ?
You know how to fix it. This is your chance.
ദ്ധ 1ദ്ഡവാഠാല്നമന്മ അല്ലാമ. ്ിഖ്ാല്ധലത്ധ
The soup! Where is the soup? Out of my way.
ട്വ! ഴി ഥോ വധ? ൭ ലി
Move it, garbage boy!
ദലാല്മിലാധഠ്ട ടല്വാട്ല്‍്‌
You are cooking?
ദ്ധ നനടടമിറ!
How dare you cook in my kitchen?
ലി ത്വ നനടടമിറഥിന ലാഖ്‌ ല്വ?!
Where do you get the gall
ഉ നന്മ ത്വ 0 ശ്ധബ്ന..
to even attempt something so monumentally idiotic?
10 ന൦ഥൊട ടട ടു ടാ 0ംഠി൦ന?
I should have you drawn and quartered!
൧൮ ടല്ാദഡസ ടല ഠ്ടബ്രമ്‌ത്ധ!
I'll do it. 1 think the law is on my side.
൧ിവ മിത്൩ില്ഡ്രയ്ുര. കഷിവ ടഃ ധനാനി നസഘ്ാലല്വ മിവ
Larousse, draw and quarter this man
1ലഠവടടം. ടല ൦ ഷഡി ബ..
after you put him in the duck press to squeeze the fat out of his head.
..ടഠിലാദട !ധ്ധില്ച്ത്ഥ ഠിദ ഠി നലം.
-What are you blathering about? -The soup!
യായ ത്വ നലമ്പാലാട ല്‌? -ടഥ്വാ്ധ!
Soup?
ടല്വാ?
Stop that soup!
റസ്പിത്ഥ ടഥ്വാധ!
Waiter.
ലലിക്ൃത്ഥ
You're fired!
ദ്ധ ഠി
F-I-R-E-D! Fired!
൧-0-2-1! ൧0൦6
She wants to see the chef.
൧9 നമ ധാലുധന്വാട 900 ഡിത്ന നട
But he...
ലവ ഠിദ-ഠിദ--
-What did the customer say? -It was not a customer. It was a critic.
൧്വാ3 0 ത്മ?
-Ego? -Solene LeClaire.
ടറുഠ?
-LeClaire? What did she say? -She likes the soup.
1 ലലില്ഭ്‌? ല്യാട ഠി ൫9 - ൧ ടധിര ട്വ
Someone is asking about your soup.
ടാ ല്ബുയ ടദി ട്വ ത്വ
What are you playing at?
യായ ത്വ നല്ബ്ത്ഥല്‌?
Am I still fired?
൧ഠിടയ മിവ നടി ഠ്ലാടംല്‌?
-You can't fire him. -What?
ദ്ധ 191൦1600൭൧ ഠി - ക്യാമ?
LeClaire likes it, yeah? She made a point of telling you so.
1ലലില്ട ടിയു? ൧9 ടാ ലന്ല്ഡത്ധ
If she write a review to that effect
പിര ഠിദ ിട ധി
and find out you fired the cook responsible...
൦ 001 1ല്ഡ ത്വ ൭ ഡി നട ലഡ്ാഥനഘയ്ലോ..
-He's a garbage boy. -Who made something she liked.
൧9 0ധഠഒ ടന്വാമവ - ന നടടല ടട ഠിദ ടിയ
How can we claim to represent the name of Gusteau
റല ന ലഗ്ന നണട വ്വട്ടദ്ധ..
if we don't uphold his most cherished belief?
യന 1മനന്ധ്യനാ ശ്വാലദേരാന്സയ്‌?
And what belief is that, Mademoiselle Tatou?
ഉബരഭ്വാലമേമന ട്വ, ഗഒറ്ലനഠ'ടല്‌ട [ 1?
Anyone can cook.
ഭലടില്വാല്യധബാഠില്‍ നണട
Perhaps I have been a bit harsh on our new garbage boy.
ഗ്ധ്ിന്൩ മിവ ാലലരടല 03ഠ്ടവാധഠ്ട ടന്ന
He has taken a bold risk
൧9 1൦50 നാന്സി ടബ്ബറ്ടിര ലി.
and we should reward that, as Chef Gusteau would have.
റ ൧ദ്ധ്ലാലെ ബുലന..
If he wishes to swim in dangerous waters,
പിര ഠിദ ന്ധ ലന്മ ഠി ഠി ൮൮) ലാട.
who are we to deny him?
..ട്ല്യാദ്ല്വിന്മ ധിനല്്മല്ദ്സ്‌?
-You were escaping? -Oh, yeah.
ദ്ധ ലിലി?
Since you have expressed such an interest in his cooking career,
ഴിനനമറഠ്ഘാത്ബിത്ധ ടാ ഠ്വ ്വിഭ്ലുമ്ര നണടട്സു..
you shall be responsible for it.
ചിരവ വാദ്യ ലാഡ്ാഥനയലാോ നന്മഠ്ലാസു
Anyone else?
൧ഠ9 ടടടില്വാ യ മന?
Then back to work.
പ്ഒഠി (സ്സാട॥ ലഭ]
You are either very lucky or very unlucky.
നണട 9 ദ്ധ ടു്ലാന്ടടി വാ! ദ്ധ ടു ല്ലാം!
You will make the soup again, and this time, I'll be paying attention.
ദ്ധ മിത്ബാധമട്‌ ടഥ്വാധ ടന്ധിട, ൦ 1യി ബി, മിവ മിതാലി ലാന്മ്ില
Very close attention.
നാമ നസ്ാലാലന്മിന
They think you might be a cook. But you know what I think, Linguini?
ഗ്0വിന്നത്ധ സ്ധഥ്്ന ടല ഡി നട
I think you are a sneaky, overreaching little...
ചവ ടട !യ്ധ ടന ॥101--
Rat!
11॥1വട!
-Rat! -Get the rat.
- ഹത്വാ ധിവടഡ
Linguini. Get something to trap it.
ധനധ്ബ. ഷ്ബാ॥ ടടട്ധദ്ധ ഥി നനംത്വാസു
It's getting away. Get it, get it, get it.
ച്റിത്വാം, ബിയ്യം, ബ്ിത്വാ
-What should I do now? -Kill it.
൧്യാ൮൬ ഠ്ധ ലിവ ഡല ടത? - ന്ധ
-Now? -No, not in the kitchen. Are you mad?
ലയഷ്ഥയാ? - ധി ഠ। ഠിന ലാഖ്‌. ദ്ധ ഠ്‌?
Do you know what would happen to us
ദ്ധ ദസ ലലാ ലാലിലിവ ാടഠ്ട ന്ദ
if anyone knew we had a rat in our kitchen?
൭ ദ ദ്ധ ദ നിവട ഠി ഠ്ല്ാധ ന്മ?
They'd close us down.
ഗന ലിത്ഥ ഡധ്വാ।ന്ദ
Our reputation is hanging by a thread as it is.
മല്ാധ്മടി ൯1 ലാഥ ഠ്ദ്വല ഠ്വ
Take it away from here. Far away. Kill it. Dispose of it. Go!
ദദഗാ [9 0ലഠ ഠി ടബ്‌. പദ്ധ. ദുധന്ധ്ന ദ. ല്വധടിയ്യ. ൧0
Don't look at me like that! You aren't the only one who's trapped.
പറ്൩ നാംനാ വ ാലറ്വ്യ! ദ്ധ ൮൮൭ "ണഇലാത്വാ!
They expect me to cook it again!
000 ലിവ നനടടട ട്രി 91!
I mean, I'm not ambitious. l wasn't trying to cook.
ഗിലിദ്ധാവ, മ്വാധിര്സമാലയ്ണ്ടെ 101. മവ ധ്യ ലോ നനടടമ
l was just trying to stay out of trouble.
ചവ ഡബനമ ലോ ധിലുദ്ധ്വ്ത്ഥ 1 ചി നടി
You're the one who was getting fancy with the spices!
ദ്ധ ൮൬൭ നന്ധലന്ധലിയ്സുര 99൩ ന്ാ-ഞ്ബട!
What did you throw in there? Oregano? No? What? Rosemary?
യായ ത്വ ദേന്ഥല്ലഭ ന ട്ട? ഠറുനാ? ലിറ ചയ? ദം൦ടനമബ?
That's a spice, isn't it? Rosemary?
൮ ടല്ലബ്ട ന്ഥ, ഒ? ദംടനമ
You didn't throw rosemary in there?
ദ്ധ 1510 ഥല്വാല്റത്ഥ ഗാടണമ്ല്‌ ൪ ഠിന ട്ട?
Then what was all the flipping and all the throwing the...
പഠി ല്വാ ൮൬൭ ഠ॥റ്ല0 0 ിഠേന്വാലിറിമ്ന--
I need this job. I've lost so many.
ചവ ലാല്ധിത്ന ഭവ ബി. ൧ിവ ഠ്൭൨ വി ബത്ര
I don't know how to cook, and now I'm actually talking to a rat as if you...
ചവ പ്ിറവല്ഡ നടം
Did you nod?
൧ഠിടിയ്നിത്ധ നഹൃബ്ാധ്റന
Have you been nodding?
ദ്ധ നഹാദധിറ
You understand me?
ദ്ധ ലിന മിവ?
So I'm not crazy!
പ്ഒഠി മിവ ാധിത്ബ്ല ദ!
Wait a second, wait a second.
പസി ടലഷ്ല്വാ, ൩ ട്വ
l can't cook, can I?
ചവ ൭0൦1ല്‍ നടനടടമ്ലിത്ഥ?
But you...
ലവ ഭ്വ--
You can, right?
ദ്ധ 10൦1൭൨. 87
Look, don't be so modest. You're a rat, for Pete's sake.
പ്ാബ്മ൨ ടല ടനാദ്‌. ദ്ധ ൨ ടല വിവട
Whatever you did, they liked it.
൧്യാട ടദ്യവ ത്൨ ഠ്ല്വാധമം ന ലിയു
Yeah. This could work.
൭. ബി സ്ഥാന ഠല്മട॥
Hey, they liked the soup!
ലല, ന്ന ഥിര ടഥ്വാധ!
They liked the soup. Do you think you could do it again?
00 ലിയ ടഥ്വാധ. ദ്ധ ഒട യവ 001൦൩0൧൭ ടര ൭917
Okay, I'm going to let you out now.
൦ മിവ ദിത്ബിലാടടിത് ത്വ ടത
But we're together on this. Right?
വല്യ 09 ലലടടന ഠിന നമ ബ്‌. ധന
So this is it.
പ്ഒഠി ബില ഠി
I mean, it's not much, but it's, you know...
ഗിലിദ്ധാവ, സര 15100 ല്വാമ-ല്വാമ ടാ ലവ, ത്൨ ലസ...
Not much.
..91ഠ090 ല്വാമ-ല്വാ 5൭൧02
It could be worse.
1ാഠില്വുദഠി। ലാബി
There's heat and light and a couch with a TV.
൧ഠ9 ഹണനട 90 ന്ധ ഠ്ബിഭബടി ഗബ്യണാ ഠേ ടബ്പസ..
So, you know, what's mine is yours.
901, ത്വ ലിസ, ലാ സി॥॥ലി്വ 199 സ്॥॥ലത്ധ
Are you...
൧റ്ഒഷ്ഗ :(൭൧.. 7
Is this a dream?
൧റ്ഒഷ്ഗ ൧൨ ഥ്‌ സ്ഥ
The best kind of dream.
707൩07) 4൦7
One we can share.
൭൭1൧ 77൩07) :ഗ്൭ 2ഠ07൭൦൦ ഈറഥറ്റ
But why here?
7ഒ൧ (കഥമ്ഥദ വ്‌ 67
Why now?
ഥാ ലേഷ7ഥറ?
Why not here?
(ഥാ ൧ാഥക് വ്‌ ഥേ?
Why not now?
(ഥാ 2൧ ടല?
What better place to dream than in Paris?
7ലന്ഥാട ൧ാലന്നന്വാ7 ൧൭) (൧൧ ൧൭% ടലഒ൭൧൨ റ്൭7്‌ ൨ ൧൭7757
Morning, Little Chef. Rise and...
റ്റി, ലനം ലല്‌. 8:൮൧ ഠ്ടന--
Idiot! I knew this would happen!
8ഠഠിഠ൨) ലവ 1ദഡ ബി ലിത്ബാലില്വ!
I let a rat into my place and tell him what's mine is his!
൧ിവ ിലിത്ഥ ടടലര വിവട നടടഥിിന..
Eggs, gone!
ലി, ഠി ലി!
Stupid! He's stolen food and hit the road! What did I expect?
8ഠഠിഠവ ൧1 ൭൨ ഡോ നിത ഠ്ദര ൭0! ക്വാ ൮൬൭ ൮ ഠ്വ?
That's what I get for trusting a...
ധിട൩൭ വ ഠ്ഠാധിഭ്മ നലസ്വലമ്വേരി ടയ 0--
Hi. Is that for me?
ഠ്യ ഥിംല്യ്‌
That's good. What did you put in this?
ല്ല്വാസമ. ലായ ത്വിപ്ലിറി। റിന്‌?
Where'd you get that?
ഉ നന്മ ത്ധ ധ്‌?
Look, it's delicious. But don't steal. I'll buy some spices, okay?
ഉല, ബര ട്ല്വ. 101൫ നല ൧ിവ മിതാ! ട൦ഠ1൩ ന്ഥ, ലിറ
Oh, no. We're going to be late. And on the first day!
൭൨, ലെ ൭ ലിയ്ഥ ലാ. ദുഠിട 0 ലാന!
Come on, Little Chef!
പഠന, ൦ ഘി!
"Though I, like many other critic,
"്ലിദ്ധ്വാഥ മിവ, ലോല ഹാഘാന്പില്ലന..
"had written off Gusteau as irrelevant since the great chef's death,
.ന്ുദാാല്വ ദ്വടഭദ്ധ ട്ധഠ്ടല്വാനസ്ഥു..
"the soup was a revelation. A spicy yet subtle taste experience."
0 വ ടടട്ധ്ധ വ ദേ മട ൮ ാഠഠിടട ദ്വി ലിഷ."
-Solene LeClaire? -Yes!
൭ഠില ലലല? -
"Against all odds, Gusteau's has recaptured our attention.
പ്രീലലസ്മനാ ട്ട സ്വന,
"Only time will tell if they deserve it."
ബസ നട ൭൨ നലലന്ധിത്ലിര ന്നിലിദുയ് നലല്ത്‌
Well...
പചന്വാമിന്ുയ--
You know.
ദ്ധ 1ലിഡ
Look, I know it's stupid and weird, but neither of us can do this alone,
൧ിവ മിഡി ൦009൦0 ഒ ലാല॥വല്വാി! യി സ്വ വഠ്൭0ഠ്വധാധമബ ടബ്(0..
so we got to do it together, right? You with me?
190 ൩1൭൬൫൭ ലിവിഖ്്സ ലട നട, യന? ദ്ധ ഠി ലവ?
So let's do this thing!
പ്ഒഠി ന വിരസ!
Welcome to hell. Now, recreate the soup.
ലന മനാ ദ നലല്യ. ലയ, ല്രാട ടന്ധിട ടഥ്വാധ
Take as much time as you need. All week if you must.
൧൩0 ടലാബഖി്നടന്മ നടത ഗലിധിത്ഥ. ടലോബുദ്സ്ഘാധ॥ിരാന്ധ
Soup.
ട്വ
You little...
൭ ൭൦1--!
You son ofa...
ദ്ധ 15൦)
You got...
ദ്ധ ൭1൨ ഠ101--
This is not going to work, Little Chef!
ബി 'പ്വിറ്ഷ്ബ്ാലന്നുടി, ല്ല ഘി!
I'm going to lose it if we do this anymore.
1-1 11-111:11-11:111: 11:11
We've got to figure out something else.
ധന നിനനത്ഥ ടട
Something that doesn't involve any biting, or nipping,
ലട നല[ാഖിക് നനാ ദ്ധ നലോ...
or running up and down my body with your little rat feet.
൭9 ലിലി ൭ ദ൭ടെ ദ്ബായ് ഠി ടവ ഠബിവിറ ധിവട ത്വ
The biting! No! Scampering! No!
ഴി! നല ലിലി നലല്‍ംസ്വാിം്ഥാമ്‌ 19%
No scampering or scurrying. Understand, Little Chef?
1101൩ ഠലിലി നലല്‍ംസ്വാിം്പാ ദ്ധ വാലി 'ണുടടദ-9ടട
Little Chef?
ലില്‍ ല്‌?
Oh, you're hungry.
ധ്പത്ധില്ാല
Okay. So let's think this out.
വിം നനിത്ഥമാന്ബ
You know how to cook, and I know how to appear
ദ്ധ 1മ്ഡവാഠാല്നമന്മ ല്നടനണടട. ൧ിവ 1മ്ഡവാഠാല്നമന്മ ല്ധഭനമ0..
human.
നഥ്ഖട്വഒ
We need to work out a system so that do what you want
ധ൭ാലി്ധാധട്‌ ടാ ടിട്ന ഥോ ദവവാധമ ലാവ ത്ധ നട്ഡ..
in a way that doesn't look like I'm being controlled by a tiny rat chef.
വോ ഭ॥അ്ദ നടഠേണന മിവ ഠ്യ ഠില൨ ടല ്ധിത്ല നടടച്ിവട (൭൦1
Would you listen to me? I'm insane! I'm insane! I'm insane!
ദ്ധ ഠി ൭0 ലിവലാലനല്ത്വാ? ൧ിവ ൭൨911൭!
In a refrigerator talking to a rat about cooking in a gourmet restaurant.
ഗന 0 ചട ലലദിത്വാ 90 ടല നിവട 1 നനടടമിറി। ൭൦ ഗഠധന്നല്‍.
-I will never pull this off! -Linguini?
൧ിവ 1ടറമ0ാലുദര ദ്ഡ്ര്ത
We gotta communicate.
ധ൭ നടട ലാലിരന്ധബിരുടി
I can't be constantly checking for a yes or no head shake from a...
൧ിവ ദവാ ടടില്ധ ലാലി ഗുണ ശ്വാമിമയ മദ 09 ടയ 0--
The rat! I saw it!
11॥വട! ചവ നന്ദ!
-A rat? -Yes, a rat. Right next to you.
വട? - ൭, വിവട. 8ദ്ധിാഒ്ധി ഠി ടലാടില്നിത്ധ
What are you doing in here?
യായ ത്ധവാധമ്ം।ഠ്ന ടബ്‌?!
I'm just familiarizing myself with, you know, the vegetables and such.
ധന നലനലമ്പാദടല്ത്ഥ ഠി 9൩, ന്ധ ല്ഡ, പേഡ ൦ ടസ്ല്ഡസുട
Get out.
ദ്ധ
One can get too familiar with vegetables, you know!
ണു ംലദഠി ലില്ധ ഭവാ ൩ ടയഡന, ഡി
That was close. Are you okay up there?
വ നല്ല. ദ്ധ ൦0 ഒട ടന്മ്‌?
How did you do that?
റ്റി യവ ധദ്ലാാധ?
That's strangely involuntary!
ധ്ധല രമി ൭ 0
One look and I knew we had the same crazy idea.
൭൭൧ ാറഠ്ദറ്റണറ റ്റ ഒ൭:൧ ൭൧0൧ ശഗ്൭ നണസ്റഥാഥ്വഷ (റ്ടെ റ) ഒന
Where are you taking me? Wait.
(൭ നന്മ ത്വ നമിവായട പവ പ്പി
Wait. I'm sorry.
പൂസ. ചവ സ്ന്മ നട്‌
That should do it.
൮ ലിത്ഥ നടിോയ്വിയ്സുര
Congratulations. You were able to repeat your accidental success.
ല്ന്സ്0൩. ദ്ധ 1൭൮1 90 നഹാധ്‌യ! ഷ്യ 1൦ ടനോല്യ്ധ
But you'll need to know more than soup if you are to survive in my kitchen, boy.
ല്വ। ദ്ധ ല്ഡ ലാ ബോ ട്വ ിരാത്ധ നല്വഷയി ൦ ഠിന ലോധ വ
Colette will be responsible for teaching you how we do things here.
൦ ലാലമ്റാഥ്്്യ്ലാ നൃല്യല ന്ധ റുണ്ട്‌ ധാധണശ്ം ടലി
Listen, I just want you to know
൧ിവ ഡനട നല്ലത്ധ ഖ്ഡ ല്ലാ.
how honored I am to be studying under such...
ലാ ബയ മ്വ ധ്ലാലല്യല ഠി ദമ
No! You listen. I just want you to know exactly who you are dealing with.
ഠി ദ്ധ ണന. ചവ ബന ന ന്ധ ല്ഡ 90 ട്ല്വാധ്ധ ബബടമന
How many women do you see in this kitchen?
ലഭ്യ ണ ഡാബ്മ റു ധ്ധ ന്യാ ടബ്‌?
Well, I...
൧ിവ--
-Only me. Why do you think that is? -Well, I...
൨൩൭ 31൨. (ദ്ധ മട അന്വ? - ൧ിവ--
Because haute cuisine is an antiquated hierarchy
ലോല ന്ധ ഖിട്നട ഒല വിന്ല്റല്യാധിം.
built upon rules written by stupid old men.
0൭ ാലഠ്ടടചിത്ഥ ഥ്ഹോ-ഥനാദ് റു ഠ്ിട ലവി സദാ
Rules designed to make it impossible for women to enter this world.
ലലെമ്ധന ഠിട്ര ഥിംനനസ്പട്ട്ലിത്ഥ ബ്ദ നനടടധിറ ബ്ബ
But still I'm here. How did this happen?
ല്വ। മവ നട ഠി ടബ്‌. റല ബിരാലില്വ?
Because, well, because you...
ലോല ത്വ...
Because I am the toughest cook in this kitchen.
൧ിവ വധി നടട്നലാട ഠി ട്‌.
I've worked too hard for too long to get here
൧ിവ ലാലല ഭട ൦ 1ണ ധി ധാലാദ ഠി ട്ല്‍
and lam not going to jeopardize it for some garbage boy who got lucky.
൧൮ 15100 നബ്ലദടിയ്യ ധി ടം ധാ ടാന്വാമ്വയലാലന്മട ൦
Easy to cook. Easy to eat. Gusteau makes Chinese food
ഗ്ധഠി൭൨ ഠിന്ടള്‍്ധഠ്ട ന്ത. വ്വട്ടധ നടനല്ല:
Chine-easy.
[11111]
-Excellent work, Francois, as usual. -It's good, isn't it?
ല)ദ ൮൬ 0റുവട, -൨ഥഠട, നേന 0195൭..
I want you to work up something for my latest frozen food concept.
ചവ നലിലത്ധ ധടദ്നല്ത്ഥ ടട ധിം 1രനടലാ നദിത്നന ഥല്‍വ ലാല മിവ
They're like corn dogs, only smaller. Bite size.
[ഗ00 നാണ ഗന 9൦, ഡന് ലാ ൪൦1. ട്വ ററി
What are corn dogs?
൧്വാട ൮ ഗന?
Cheap sausages dipped in batter and deep fried. You know, American.
ടല സന്ധത ഠിം ദിന ഠാധ്്മ ൦ 9൦ 990 ദന സ്സ
Whip something up.
8ധ൭ ടടേട്ധദ്ധ ല്ലോ
Maybe Gusteau in overalls and Huckleberry Tom hat.
ഗലി ന്൩ ഡടടദ്ധ ഠിീന്ന ലയി 9൩1൦0 ധഠഠിലാ്ു "ഗണ
Or as a big ear of corn in doggie make-up.
ഷട്ധ ടലാമറു നാ ലാട ഠി ഠനനട്ത്വാ ബു
Yes. But, please, with dignity.
ലവ, ഠ്ലാന്ധേ നബ
Get my lawyer!
ലദ്്റ॥ ഗടറ്ധനണ മയ്‌
Well, the will stipulates
൧്വാ ൮൬ ഡാടി് വധ സത്ലിത്ഥ..
that if after a period of two years from the date of death
യ ടലിലാടട ന്വാ൦൨ 2 ദ്ഥ ണം ലിന ണമിഒല..
no heir appears,
109 ഡലിട ന്ധ...
Gusteau's business interests will pass to his sous chef. You.
ഭ്യാസ ാസ്പമാമ ഡട്ട്ധ..
I know what the will stipulates.
൧ിവ 1ദിഡ ല്ാ൮൬ ധാടിദ്്ഡ സത്ലിത്ഥ
What I want to know is if this letter... If this boy changes anything!
൧൮ 3൮ നല്ഡാല്ല്വവിരയ ടമ്ബ ിതവാധഠ്ച്്ധ നധാട ല്വാ-ല്വാമ!
There's not much resemblance.
ദാസി ലാലടണമന
There's no resemblance at all. He is not Gusteau's son.
11909 ലട നടന. ൧9 ധിത്ഥ ഇല ്വട്ടധ
Gusteau had no children, and what of the timing of all this?
ദ്ട്ലാധ മ നന്പധധസുയി നലം,
The deadline in the will expires in less than a month!
ദ്ധ ഒഥിന ലിത്ഥ ണന ഠിന നടടഃ വമ നോ ടലാധിദ്്‌
Suddenly, some boy arrives with a letter
1109-0൭, 5൦0 ധഠ്ചസ്ാഃ ൩0 ട്ല്ലാധഡിം ടമ.
from his recently deceased mother claiming Gusteau is his father?
0൬0 1ാധസു൭൮൭ലാബ നവാ! ബ്ദ നാവി ദവട്ഭദ്ധ ടല മയൂര?
Highly suspect!
നാമ്‌ നറഥററല്ത്ല്‍്‌
-This is Gusteau's? -Yes, yes, yes.
ബി സ ദ്ധട്ടദ്ധ? ര,
-May I? -Of course.
8൦1൩ മിവ? - ൧൨ ന്വ
But the boy does not know.
ല്വവാധഠ്ല്ഡ ല്മ്ഡ
She claims she never told him, or Gusteau, and asks that I not tell.
൧9 യ ഠി 1൭ ണന ന്ല്ഡ ഠി,
-Why you? What does she want? -A job for the boy.
(ന്യാ ദ്ധ ക്വാ ൮൬൭ ഠി ന്ലവ്ഡ? - ദ്ധ ലാലല. ധി ഥ്ധാല്ല്ധ
-Only a job? -Well, yes.
൨ ബ൭ ട്വ വാലശ്ല്മ്ന്‌?
Then what are you worried about? If he works here,
പഠി ല്വാ ൮൬൭ ൭൮ നല്ടധിത്ന?
Find out how much of this is real.
ദ ല്ല്വാ സ്യ ബി
I will need you to collect some DNA samples
ചവ നലിലിത്വ ഠില്വദ്ിത്ഥ ട൭ഠി॥0 ൦0൩൦0 ൧1൭൧..
from the boy. Hair, maybe.
൭0 ധഠ്ട്ല്ഡ. ലമ്പാധ,, സ്ഥാന
Mark my words. The whole thing is highly suspect.
ിതത്ല്വ: ടല്ധ്ഡ്ലബി ടാ നഥഥാല്ത്ഥ
He knows something.
൧ വല്ഡ ടടട്ധമ്ധ
Relax, he's a garbage boy. l think you can handle him.
8, ഠി ധാ ടന്വാമവ ചവ ടട യ്ധ 001൦൩ ധബടിത്ഥ ഠി
What are you doing?
യായ ത്ധവാധമ്ല്‌?
I'm cutting vegetables. I'm cutting vegetables?
൧൮ ടഠഠ്യാ 0൦ ടഡ. ൧൮ ടട 0൦ ടഡന?
No! You waste energy and time!
ഠി (ദ്ധ നന്സാമമ്ലത്ഥ ന്മാ ഠി നട!
You think cooking is a cute job, like Mommy in the kitchen?
ദ്ധ ൫൭൭ നനടടല്ലക്ടം ഠേണട, നേന 0൮ ഠി ഠ്ച്വാഥ?
Well, Mommy never had to face
1 1ദലാല്മ മില്‌ ഭടടടദ്ത്ഥ നിത നമിടന..
the dinner rush when the orders come flooding in,
ിദ്ധിരവാബുത്്ലാടമന്മ നടി.
and every dish is different and none are simple,
ടലി നമ൭൫൦൩ ലാല, ൪9൮൬ ന്ധഠ്ല, നട നടടല്യ്ഥ ാലാടാ..
but must arrive on the customer's table
901 നടട॥ ട്വ ഭ നല 03ഠ്മ നട ടട, ൧095 0 ടല്വധന്മ!
Every second counts, and you cannot be Mommy!
ലില്യാ ടമ ൩9, ത്വ 1 ധംലദഠി വധ!
What is this? Keep your station clear!
൧്യാട ബി? ഒലഭ്ര്വ്ത്ഥ സ്വാബ്ിത്ധ!
When the meal rush comes, what will happen?
8॥5 ഭടടട്ത്ഥ നടിത്ന്ഥ ടന്വാടി, ദ്വാദ മിര്ബാലില്വ?
Messy stations slow things down.
1ല്വാബ്൮യ ടണം നലന്വലിദ്ബ്ത്ിക്ലു
Food doesn't go, orders pile up. Disaster.
1-111-11: 1111-17 ഗടടറബാലന്മ്പാലി
I'll make this easy to remember.
൧ിവ മിത്ബാധമ് ബി സ്ധാദ ഥി ന
Keep your station clear, or I will kill you!
ലട്ടിവത്ഥ ന്വാമ്ധിത്ധ, ദ്ധ മിവ ലിത്ബാധസ്ധ്വത്ധ!
Your sleeves look like you threw up on them.
1 ല്റുബാല്യ ത്വ നന്നേ യ്ധ 9൭0 സ്വന ഠ ദ്ര
Keep your hands and arms in, close to the body. Like this. See?
ഉടൂട്ലിക്ഥ ന ദിനോ ഠി ദിന, ല്‍ ൩ 03ഠ൭൩
Always return to this position.
ലട സ്പാ !ഭ ംടിട। ല്‍
Cooks move fast. Sharp utensils, hot metal, keep your arms in.
ധിയാ നടടമിവാലുല്ല് ലോട്‌. ലലെ ലയന,
You will minimize cuts and burns and keep your sleeves clean.
ദ്ധ മിത്൨ ന്ബസ്ധമ്ത്ഥ വിര ഠ്ബര്ധാല്യ്..
Mark of a chef: Messy apron, clean sleeves.
09 ടല ഡി നടടല്൦ ൧൮000 ൪൦0൦, ൭൩ ലട
I know the Gusteau style cold.
൧ിവ 1ല്ഡ ടാ ഡട്ടദ്ധ
In every dish, Chef Gusteau always has something unexpected.
ഗന ടഖബില്വാ നമി,
I will show you. I memorize all his recipe.
൧ിവ മിത്0 ഡബധ്ലാടഠ്ദ ത്വ. ൧ിവ ൫൭൭ ടന്ധട ടട! ഠിദ
-Always do something unexpected. -No. Follow the recipe.
ല്സിടട ധ്‌ ടട ലാര 11990 വടട!
-But you just said that... -No, no, no.
വല്യ ദ്ധ ത്മ
It was his job to be unexpected. It is our job to...
ഠ്വ ഠിദ ധിം നബി ഡല 11൭൭൧0. ൧9൭1 ഭവ ന ധി൦..
-Follow his recipes. -Follow the recipe.
॥ഡ ടട! 919
How do you tell how good bread is without tasting it?
റ്റാ !ധ്ധ ല്ഡ വധ ടംഠിട് 1ല്യാട നലമടല്സുമ?
Not the smell, not the look, but the sound of the crust.
ധി ദ്ധ, ാധിത്ല സ്വാ, 11 സി വി
Listen.
ഉല
Symphony of crackle. Only great bread sound this way.
ടന്ന്൦ബ ലട ൨ബസ൭ 00൮൬൭ ്ട ലാനസ്ധസ്ി ാല്റ്ബ
The only way to get the best produce is to have first pick of the day
ാധ-ടദ്ധസര ലേ 10 നല ന൯൭ട॥ ലാലി.
and there are only two way to get first pick.
൨൩൭ 309 2 ലേ ധി നല്ലാ! 0110 ലാലറന്മണനട:
Grow it yourself, or bribe a grower.
0ണ ടാ, മ്ദ്ധ മട്ധലാന്മന്മന
Voila! The best restaurant get first pick.
109! ൭5൧൫൭0 നാലി വയ നന്മ്ല്ാ
People think haute cuisine is snooty. So chef must also be snooty.
ഥു മഥ ബേട്ട ലി യ
But not so. Lalo there ran away from home at 12.
ലവ ധാ. 13൦ ൮, ൭0 ഠി ബന നടടഃ 19 12 ന്ഥ
Got hired by circus people as an acrobat.
ഉ്സ॥ 0൭ഭ)ദ ൦1൦0 മല ടലിതരട ടലാദദ! ന
And then he get fired for messing around with the ringmaster's daughter.
ലവ ന്ധ 90൭൦4 ഷമ്മ ബീ
-Horst has done time. -What for?
൨൦൫൮ ഠ്ലാലബ്്ലിത്ഥ - (ലന ദ്വാമ?
No one know for sure. He changes the story every time you ask him.
11909 ടില്വാ ൮൬ സ. ൧൭ ധാമ ലേ ടലിലാ ര ധ്വര ഠി
defrauded a major corporation.
൧ിവ വാവ ടലാധമ ഒര്ഥിയ്ലാടടല
l robbed the second largest bank in France using only a ballpoint pen.
൧ിവ ഗ്വാമിവാബ്ലിരഠ്ധട 'നോടടല ഠി ലല്ഥഠിട..
Il created a hole in the ozone over Avignon.
൧ിവ വാവ ടമ ധാ ഠ। ൦൦0൦ ഒട ൧ഡറ്0൦൩
I killed a man with this thumb.
൧ിവാധന്ധ ടം 1൦10 പാഡി
Don't ever play cards with Pompidou.
പറ൩ നല്൩ര൦ 90 ം്വഠ്ല
He's been banned from Las Vegas and Monte Carlo.
൧9 1൦50 0ലല്ിത്ഥ ഠ 135 ഡാടട ഴി ഠിം
-Larousse ran gun for the Resistance. -Which resistance?
1ലഠടട൦ നലറ്റയാഡ്‌ ടടന്ല്വാനാ 1 ലട
He won't say. Apparently, they didn't win.
൧9 10 ദവിയ്വാ. പ്ല്ദടല൨, സ്ിനല്നടന്മണാ
So you see.
പഠി !യ്വ
We are artist, pirate. More than cooks are we.
[൭ 96190 ബിട, സ്ഥ. 1൭0110 ചി ടലരഠ്ച ധി നടട
-We? -Oui. You are one of us now, oui?
൭? - ൭. രവ ടി ടയ ണോ യി ടലിത്ഥമ, ദര്‌?
Oui. Thank you, by the way, for all the advice about cooking.
ലണ!൭ടി॥൨ മട ടു നട102 1 നനടടമ!
-Thank you, too. -For what?
“ലന്മതരടിവധാദ - പന്ധില്വാ?
For taking it.
ലന നാമ്പു
The rat!
വട യി
-But he is a... -I just dropped my keys.
ലവ ഠിദ-- - കവ ഡനദ ലുദ്ധ്വത്ിവ ലിവ്‌
Have you decided this evening?
ദ്ധ ഠ്ദ്വാധശ്ാധ്ധടാന നടിണ ബ്‌?
-Your soup is excellent. But... -But we order it every time.
ടല്വാ ന്ധ ട൦ഠില്വ. 1ല്വാ1-- - [ല്യി യണ്‌ നണട ടബില്വാിരി
-What else do you have? -Well, we have a very nice foie gras.
൧്വാ 91൮൭ ത്വ ദ? - ദ്വി മഠ "വ 90൭5 ൮൬൭ ട൦ഠില്വ--
I know about the foie gras.
൧ിവ ദ്ധ ലാട ഗി റ്ലടട
The old standby, used to be famous for it.
ലെറ്റുസി ന, 0൦൩20 ലിലി ഘന
What does the chef have that's new?
൧്യാ൮൬ ഡി നടടലിമ്ട൬ാബ്‌?
-Someone has asked what is new! -New?
ടാ സര ദ്യ ലാബി!
Yes. What do I tell them?
൧്വാട മിവ നമ ധന്ല്ഡ ന്ന്൪
-Well, what did you tell them? -I told them I would ask!
൧്യായത്വ 950 ന്ല്ഡ ന്നറ - ന വ ത്ഥ ബര!
What are you blathering about?
യായ ത്വവാലാലിത്ല?
-Customers are asking what is new. -What should I tell them?
ലിബ്ര ഖാ ബബ - ൧൮൭ 31൮ നിവാല്ല്ഡ ന്നറ
-What did you tell them? -I told them I would ask!
൧്യായത്വ 950 ന്ല്ഡ ന്നറ - ന വ ത്ഥ ബര!
This is simple.
ബി സ്ധ്ല
Just pull out an old Gusteau recipe,
എ്വ॥ ടല്യദ ടദ്ധ ടട നണട ദ്വട്ടമ്ധ,
something we haven't made in a while...
ട്ട ൮൬ ൭ ടവ ൭ [നട 191വാധമ--
They know about the old stuff. They like Linguini's soup.
ഗ്0വല്ഡ വാട! വ്്മോദ്നിടണട. [00 ലിര ട്വ നാഥ്‌
They are asking for food from Linguini?
ഗ്0ധാബസമിഖ്ല നല്ത്ന ഇം ധ്‌
A lot of customers like the soup. That's all we are saying.
നമ ലാന ടധിര ട്വ. വ ടല ൭ബ ന്ല്ല്ത്ലിത്ഥ
Were we saying that?
൧ഠടയ ന ലാലിത്ദലാല്ഡ?
Very well. If it's Linguini they want,
ലിറ. പിയ ധ്‌ ൮൭ ന്ഥി൦ന്ല്സ..
tell them Chef Linguini has prepared something special for them.
൧ലില്ഡ സ്ധിഗ്ധര്നാ നടിയ...
Something definitely off menu.
ലട ലാട വ 09ഠി ന്ധ
Oh, and don't forget to stress
ഉബയസിധാട ധിവലത്ബ്ത്ഥ..
-its Linguini-ness. -Oui, chef.
ച്നുര "നധ്ബ-ടടട"
Now is your chance to try something worthy of your talent, Linguini.
നാ ബി ഥാല്ധനാ ത്വ ധിം ഖോ.
A forgotten favorite of the chef's, sweetbread a la Gusteau.
(റുനണലന ധിര്ാ നടടമിവു ടി ിധ്വാല: സ്വാ മല്ലി ദ ഡട്ടദ്ധ
-Colette will help you. -Oui, chef.
൦ ലിരബാ്ധത്ധ - ൭, ബല്‌
Now, hurry up. Our diners are hungry.
ടന, ലോട്‌. ലലാ ന്൯ ഠ്ടവില്വാ
Are you sure? That recipe was a disaster.
൧ഠിടിയ്നത്ധ ഹ? ലട ബിം
Gusteau himself said so.
നിം
Just the sort of challenge a budding chef needs.
ബില ടദ്ധ ലോ ന്ധ്ര്നാ നടിയ നല ല്ധ്ത്ഥ
"Sweetbread a la Gusteau.
"ന്വാട ന്മി്ലി്പ്ധ ലട ദവട്ഭദ്ധ
"Sweetbread cooked in a seaweed salt crust
"ന്വാട മന്ലിലില്പധ്ധ ഠിനടടപ്്ിന ഭം ന ബന്ധാ! 3ല..
"with cuttlefish tentacle, dog rose purée,
99൩0 ന്മ ടം തല്ല 007൭൦ 9൦ 6ഠ05൭..
"geoduck egg, dried white fungus?
..൦ ൭൦൦ വിദ്ധി?
"Anchovy licorice sauce."
൭ഠട വിട ത്ഥ ലഭ"
I don't know this recipe, but it's Gusteau's, so...
൧ിവ ദവസ ടടല്ര! ബി, 11 19 ൩ ദ്വട്ടധ, ഠി.
Lalo! We have some veal stomach soaking, yes?
1൦! ന 309 0 ഠാ നല്ല്മ്ബാധ ൮൮) നാണ, ത?
Yes! The veal stomach, I get that.
ച ഡ്‌ ഠ്ഠാനാ മന്ല്ലിന്സാഖ, ട്വ മ്വ॥ത്ഥ വധ
Veal stomach?
ലെഡ്‌ ഠാ നല്ലലമ്പാധ?
I'll be right back. Where...
൧൮ മിത ഭ്വാദ॥
Hey, I got to...
ലി, ടവ (൭൫൭--
Don't mind me. I just need to borrow this real quick.
ബാധിത മിവ. ൧ിവ ബന നബ ബി ടലഭ്യല്വാ!
Let's see, over here...
മീലി 9 ഠ ട്ബി--
I'll be back.
൧ിവ മിത ഭ്വാദ॥!
Excuse me. I'm going to...
ഗിഠീര്ഥ മിവ. ൧൨ നല
Apparently, I need this. I'll be right...
പ്ല്ദടഒ൨ മവ വാലിധിത്ഥ ബ്‌. ഷിവ ലിത്ഥ (ഭ്സാദ॥--
I'm going to pick that up.
ഷിവ ലിത്ഥ ്സ॥ വ
I got some of that spice.
൧ിവ മഠ ന്ഥ
What are you doing? You're supposed
ദ്ധ ലാവ ടലഠില്ഖ്ഥ ടലി വ്വട്ടധയഡ
This is the recipe.
്ില്നടട്ല്സര
The recipe doesn't call for white truffle oil!
ലട വ ദലിത 9 ന്ദ യില ാഥിവ്‌
What else have you... You are improvising?
൧്വാട 199൮൭ ത്വ--? ദ്ധ ടടഠ് ധോട്ബ്ത്ന?
This is no time to experiment. The customer are waiting.
വാഡി നട 1 ധലലദ്വാല്നനെ. ലലിബ്ഠയാദന ടട നലഡ്ഥവ
You're right. l should listen to you!
ധാ]. കവ ടലാദ്ധസര റോ ദ്വിത്വാ।ത്ധ!
-Stop that! -Stop what?
റസ്പിത്ഥ ധി! - 1സ്ിത്ഥ ല്വാമ?
Freaking me out! Whatever you are doing, stop it.
ഴിലല്ഡിത്ഥ വി! ൧്യാട ട്വ ൮൬ ടടഠ്ത്ധാധ, ലല്ല
-Where is the special order? -Coming!
[ഗന ഹടടബിട്നട ധ്‌? - ൧!
-l thought we were together on this. -We are together.
ചവ ഉത്ഥാന ലാലടാണട ഠിന നമി ബി -ഴിനമ്റവര
-Then what are you doing? -It's very hard to explain.
ല്ല്ാിട മാ ൮൬ യവ മലി? - ബസ ടധിത്വ ധന്ധിറ്(ാത്ഥ
-The special? -Come get it!
ഹാ നമെ? ഗ്ലി മ്പ!
Whoa, whoa. I forgot the anchovy licorice sauce.
൧൮ 1ല്ധ്വാട ട൦ട ശട ിത്ബിട
-Don't you dare. -I'm not, I'm not. I'm...
പത്്ിര്ധധാ്ബി വ ധിരന. കവ ാധിത്ഥ. കിവ--
Sorry.
[11:10
Is Linguini's dish done yet?
൧ഠടയ ബ്ന ലധ്ബ്‌ ദ ട്ല്വാ?
Ja. It's as bad as we remember. Just went out.
൭.1൭ ടലി ട്രാ ലാവ യി 0൭. 8ംബ ടല ഷ്ധല
-Did you taste it? -Ja, of course, before he changed it.
൧ഠിട്യ്നധ്ധ നമമട?
Good. What? How could he change it?
മമറ്റ്ട. ൧൮൭ 8മദ്ന്മനമ ഠിദ ഠി നലാധാ്സയത്‌?
He changed it as it was going out the door!
൧ നാലാ ഷ്വിര ടഃ ശ്ധല ക്ലി ന്ധ!
They love it!
0 ധിയ്യ്ുല്‍!
Other diners are already asking about it, about Linguini.
ലലിബ്യാദനി്നാഥ ഠ്ടന്ധ്ം ബര നറാന്മ്സഭമ, റ ൨നാധ്ബി
I have seven more orders!
൧ിവ മഠ9 7 99] ടട!
That's wonderful.
ഡാ്ധടിട
I'd like one of those.
ചവ നല ടദ്ധയ വ്വ
Special order!
ടെടകബിട്ണ!
What is that?
്വാ ധ്‌?
Special order! Special order! Special order!
ടെടദബിട്ണ! ലലടടന! ടെടകബിട്ണ!
To Linguini.
(്യാദഠ ന്ധ്ബ്‌
-Congratulations, Mr. Linguini. -Cheers, ja?
ല്ന്സ്0, 20൨. ഥ്ബ
Drink now, there's plenty.
ഗിസ്ധന ടലഷ്ഥ, 39 ാബ൭
Take a break, Little Chef. Get some air.
ലല്ല, ല്ല ഘ്‌. ൧ന്ബ॥ ട൦ഠിന൩ധാല്
We really did it tonight.
ധവാന്ലാല്ല ലുദ്ധര ന്ന ബി
Got your toque.
ഉല്ല ത്വ
Oh, seriously now.
൭൨, ടല്ധടിമ ടല്ത്മ
I'd love to have a little talk with you, Linguini, in my office.
൧ിവ ന്മിവാല്ത്വാ ഠഠ൩ത്ധ ട൦ം॥൩, ധനുധ്ബ്‌. ൧ ദിന ല്ലാ വ
-Am [ in trouble? -Trouble? No.
൧ഠടയി മിവ ന നടടല്ട്ന -ഗ്ടടില്? 11%
A little wine, a friendly chat. Just us cooks.
൭൭൦ഠ10% ഡല്0, ലാലാധലി-ാധടി. ബറ ത്ഥ നട
The plongeur won't be coming to you for advice anymore, eh, Colette?
ധിയാ 0950 ൩൮ ലാത്ഥ നന്മ നടിനമത്ധഖയ!, ൨, ൦6?
He's gotten all he needs.
൧9 91 ഠ്ല്വാ ടലി ൮ ഠിദലാല്ധിത്ഥ
Toasting your success, eh, Linguini?
ഴിലഘിതഭ്യദ്മാബത്വ, ൨. ല്ല?
Good for you.
ദമറ്്ടിമറ ഥിലത്വഖ
I just took it to be polite. don't really drink, you know.
൧ിവ ഡേനട നലറ്യമന്പിസഭമ ടലാദാദി 10ഠ9 ടാ. ലവ 1൭0 സഗ്ധന, ര്ധ ലിസ
Of course you don't. I wouldn't either if l was drinking that.
വ ലനസ്ധിംവ്ചം ഷ്വലാഥ റ ന്ഥി ദിവ സ്ഗ്ധന വധ
But you would have to be an idiot of elephantine proportions
ല്വ। ദ്വ ന്ധ 0ഠഠി൦വ ൩൭ ടമ.
not to appreciate this '61 Chateau Latour.
പിയ ദ നഘൃാഘല ഗ്മടദ്ധ 1൭00 61ല
And you, Monsieur Linguini, are no idiot.
ഉബിത്വ, 77൧054ഥെ എബി, ധിത്ബി്ല്വാഠഠ്ം
Let us toast your non-idiocy.
ഗി ൩൭ അിത്നഭ്ധാല്റാംാംന്മ്നത്ഖ
-Remy! -Emile?
ലസി നിദ?
I can't believe it! You're alive!
൧ിവ 1മിവാഥമുല്‍! ദ്ധ നടി വോ!
-You made it! -I thought I'd never see you guys again!
൧ിവ ൫൭5 ലിവ ലിനമബ്ധ്വാ യി!
We figured you didn't survive the rapids.
ബി നധത്ധ ലഭി! ഠിന ടി ടയ
And what are you eating?
യായ ത്ധ നദി?
I don't really know.
11:11]
I think it was some sort of wrapper once.
൧ിവ ഒട 19 ലാനണമ്വുദഠി। ന്ധാഥ്യ്വട നമിത
What? No. You're in Paris now, baby. My town.
യാമ? 1100 !(്ധ ലാ ഠി മിട ടലഷ്വമ്റ, വ. 8ഒന്ച മിവ
No brother of mine eats rejectamenta in my town.
11909 ലാനാ വവ നദ്ത്ഥ ലവ ധന ഠ ഖല മിവ
Remy! You are stealing? You told Linguini he could trust you.
ലസ് ധ്ധ നല? ദ്ധ ന്ല്ഡ നയ്‌ ഠ്വാഠില്വാലമര്ത്ത്വ
-And he can. It's for my brother. -But the boy could lose his job.
൧0 ഠിദ 01൭1. 9 ലലാ മിവ - [ല്വി ധാല്ധ്ധ ധാം ഭ്വിദ്ബരക്ലു
Which means I would, too. It's under control, okay?
വനാ ട്നലിന്മ ലിവ്്ധാ3. 1൩൭ ലിമി, ന
-More wine? -l shouldn't, but... Okay.
മവ? - 19 ലോധ, ്വ1--
So, where did you train, Linguini?
പഠി, ഠി നന്മ ത്വ നാഥ, ധനധ്ബ്‌?
Train? All right.
ലിന്‌? ഒലി
Surely you don't expect me to believe this is your first time cooking?
ലസ്ധിട്നിത്ധ ലന്മില്വ ലമ ൩ ൭ ഹാല !യ്ധ നനടടല്റ്‌
-It's not. -I knew it!
ഴി 19 - കവ ൭0൨ ഠ്ട്ല്‍്‌
It's my... Second, third, fourth... Fifth time.
ബസ ൨൭൮൭ ഭാ, ഭാ, ഭലമ്പാ്‌, ഭിന്ദ
Monday was my first time.
ടല ഠ്വ ഹാന്മനട്്വ
But I've taken out the garbage lots of times before that...
ല്വാ। മവ ാനണ്ല്വായോ ശ്ധല ടന്വാമവ ബസരി! ടലാല്ധന യ
Yes, yes. Have some more wine.
൮൭. [ഗിസ്ന ഠ ഡ്ല
Tell me, Linguini, about your interests.
ദലന്ല്ഡ മവ, എബി, ബ്ബ നനബത്ധ
-Do you like animals? -What? Animals? What kind?
ദ്ധ ടിയ 0? ൧്യാമ? 80? പട ല്വാമ?
The usual, dogs, cats, horses, . . guinea pigs,
നാ ടമ ൧൩൭, വന, വം, വിവട 8ല്‍യ3..
rats.
വട
l brought you something to... No, no, no, no!
൧ിവ ായ്ലിത്ിത്ധ ടട ധി 119 നിദ പിഠ്ദ്ഠ്ട്റ
Spit that out right now!
ധധാദ്വി്ധ ടലത്്യ്ധാട!
Il have got to teach you about food. Close your eyes.
൧ിവ ഭന0൭ ല്യം ത്ധ നു നിത. ധ്ധ്ാ നട്ട ത്വ
Now take a bite of... No! No! No!
ലയ 91915൩ ബി-- ഠ്‌ നിഠ്ച്റ നിഠ്ല്റ്‌
-Don't just hork it down! -Too late.
പാബ്‌ 0 ട്വ! - ൧൨ ലിസാ
Here.
റ
Chew it slowly. Only think about the taste.
ധബയയ്വ ഹലില്മന-1ലമ്. റബ നിനിത്ഥ മാ ടടബുര
-See? -Not really.
പൂ്വാല്റ്‌ - [പിധ്ധാഃ
Creamy, salty sweet, an oaky nuttiness.
8ലിന്ന, നടട്ന-നടബ്ട. ടാ രാ ഠ്‌
-You detect that? -Oh, I'm detecting nuttiness.
ദ്ധ ഭട? - വ നഹാടടന ഭ്യാിദ്ല
Close your eyes. Now taste this.
ധ്ധ് നട ത്വ. ടല്ിഷ്നാ ടെല്‍
Whole different thing, right? Sweet, crisp, slight tang on the finish.
ദ്വ ട്ലാനാടമ, ന7
-Okay. -Now, try them together.
ലവ, ഖോഃ ന്0ിലലടനണട
I think I'm getting a little something there.
൧ിവ ടട മിവ 01 ടം ടടടധഡ ഠി ടാന്മ
-It might be the nuttiness. -See?
9 സ്ഥാന ടം ൭ പ്ല
-Could be the tang. -That's it.
ഗ്ല ന്൩ഭ്വാ്ം്സു൭ - ധി ഠിദ
Now, imagine every great taste in the world
മപൃ്യിയ് ടപില് ടം ഘാദ്‌ ഠി റ്രബ്മ..
being combined into infinite combinations.
..ഠിഠുപ്ധാധനാത്ന നബുദഠി। രമ്വ്മടി റു വ ൫3൧൦
Tastes that no one has tried yet! Discoveries to be made!
മട ദ ടില്വാ ണന ലോ 1൭91! €ലടസ്ധന ലിത്ഥ ധ്‌
I think...
൧ിവ ഒടമ--
-You lost me again. -Yeah.
ന്ധ 90 ഭവി ലവ ടര 1
But that was interesting.
വല്യ ടാനാമ നന്മ
Most interesting garbage I ever... What are we doing?
ന്വാദ്വാഠ!ന നടന്മഥിംല്വ ഥണടന-- ൧്യാ൮൬ ൭ 0ധ൭ലീ?
Dad doesn't know you're alive yet!
൧൭൨ ലമ്ഡാത്ധ നടി വെ.
We've got to go to the colony! Everyone will be thrilled!
ഗി ഭ രിം! ല്ധട ൦ ൭൨ മട ലഡ്വ
-Yeah! But... -What?
ച! നല്വ!-- യാമ?
Thing is, I kind of have to...
8൭ ബി, മിവ ടടഠല1 നടട॥ 0ധ9--
What do you "have to" more than family?
യായ ത്വ "നട ധ്‌ ലാ! ഇ ഷ്ധ്ുമ്‌?
What's more important here?
൧്യാ൮യ ലാവാ?
Well, I...
൧ിവ--
It wouldn't hurt to visit.
1 ട്ല്വ്വിര നല
-Have you had a pet rat? -No.
ദ്ധ 309 വിവട ലാലിന്‌? - 119910
-Did you work in a lab with rats?
൧ഠിട്യ്ന ത്വ ലഭ ഠ। നലിന്ന്മി ൮൭ നലന്വധബുയി നിവട? - 119
Perhaps you lived in squalor at some point?
൧ഠിടിയ്നര്ധ വന ൦ ന്യം 03ഠി9 ടവ നട്‌? - 19
You know something about rats! You know you do!
ദ്ധ ലസ ടട ലാട നിവട! ദ്ധ 1്ഡാത്ധ ധ്‌
You know who know do whacka-doo. Ratta-tatta.
ദ്ധ ലസ ടില്വാദ ലഡ. ദം അ--
-Hey! Why do they call it that? -What?
ലിലി! (ല്വാട ന്ഥി ലാ! വാല്ധ? - ക്യാമ?
Ratatouille. It's like a stew, right? Why do they call it that?
മടി. 2 നദമേന ടത (൭റ്വാ സ്വാ! 3 ാലറ്റ്ധ?
If you're going to name a food,
പര ധ്ധ നല നനല്യ്ഥ നദിത്വന,
you should give ita name that sounds delicious.
യ്ധ 1൩൭ ലാല നന ൮൭ ബ്ര ടല്ല്വാ
Ratatouille doesn't sound delicious. It sounds like "rat" and "patootie."
ഖാലി ദവാ ടടഠ്ല്യാ. ദവസ നേന "൭ ൦ "ദ്ധ
Rat patootie. Which does not sound delicious.
വാങി. നാ 1൭ ധാലാധസി ടലഠിട്വാ
Regrettably we are all out of wine.
:1:11-11:11:11:11 11] :11-1ി
My son has returned!
൧0൫൭1൦ ലവ ലില്വര്പാല!!!
And finding someone to replace you for poison checker has been a disaster.
൧0൫ നലാലി ടട ബാ 10 നലറ്റുസിത്ഥത്ധ..
Nothing's been poisoned, thank God, but it hasn't been easy.
11909 ല്വാ ൮൬൭ ലല അമല, ടട ലില്ല്വി ാധിത്ബ്ല സ്ധഠ്ടന
-You didn't make it easy. -l know. lam sorry, Dad.
ദ്ധ 150 നന്ന്ധദിര്സഭ ന്ധ - കവ ല്ഡ. ചവ സന്ദ നാല്‌, മര
Well, the important thing is that you're home.
നാ സ്നഭത്ധ ടല
-Yeah, well, about that... -You look thin. Why is that?
൭, ലാലിഭഗബ്ധ-- - ദ്ധ നന്ല0ദലവബട. !(ഒന്്വാമ?
A shortage of food, or a surplus of snobbery?
(വനന നിത, ദ്ദ ഗലനന്ധാല്മ്ഥ ടിയ്വാ ബിഡ്‌
It's tough out there in the big world all alone, isn't it?
ഒഖിത്വ ലാ ടട ഠ്‌ ഠി വല ടട, ഖന?
Sure, but it's not like I'm a kid anymore.
“ലസ്ധിട, ലവ! വാധ്വ!
-Hey. Hey, boy. What's up? -l can take care of myself.
൧ിവ ൦1൩3 ഠ്0ിവ ടാ
I've found a nice spot not far away, so I'll be able to visit often.
൧൮ ഠ്ദ്വൃഥന്ാട ടട ന്പോമ!..
Nothing like a cold splash of reality to make you...
11909 ല്വാമ ൮൬൭ ടല്രാല 193110 ലമി ടധിത്വ..
-Visit? -I will. l promise. Often.
ഴില്ദഗമ? - ക്വ ലിഖ. ചവ. ടലില്ധ
-You're not staying? -No. It's not a big deal, Dad. I just...
ദ്ധ 150ന്ലവ്ഘാട?
You didn't think l was going to stay forever, did you?
൧൭൨ ലവാംിന ലവ ല്ത്ഥ ഘാ! ടല, യന
Eventually, a bird's got to leave the nest.
ചന്സ്ൂ൭ ടട ാധസഡനാ നടട॥! 1ാടിത്ഥ ലാസ
We're not birds. We're rats.
ധവാധിര്ബാധഡനാ. 'ഗ്൭ ലിം നിവട
We don't leave our nests. We make them bigger.
൭ ചധഘാദിത്ന ടവ !ന൭. ഗ്ടദഠി॥൭൩സ൭ലലിവാടട്
-Well, maybe I'm a different kind of rat. -Maybe you're not a rat at all.
ഗലി ന്൩ മിവബ്ട വിവട ൮൬൭ നെമ ഗ്ധിന്സത്ധാധിഖ്സര നിവട
Maybe that's a good thing.
ഗലി ന്൩്ധവാലിത്വയ വാട
Hey! The band's really on tonight, huh?
ദഹ ധവാന്നന ്ബബോലിംന്ല്ടന ലി, ന
Rats. All we do is take, Dad.
11॥വട. ൧൧൭൮൬൭ 1൯൩൭ വ ഥുത്വ്ലവ നാമ്നാ, ഖര
I'm tired of taking. l want to make things.
൧ിവ ഠ്ദ്വി്ലി നമ്പി. ൧൮ നമവാധമ ടട
I want to add something to this world.
൧ിവ നമവാധമ ടട ധി ബി
-You're talking like a human. -Who are not as bad as you say.
ദ്ധലാലഥാലിയ്വാ നേന നബ്വടിട
-Oh, yeah? What makes you so sure? -Oh, man.
ധപ? ചാ ൮൬൭ നന്പ്ധലിത് ത്വ ാല്റ്ധാടട്ലി?
I've been able to observe them at a close-ish sort of range.
൧ിവ 11 ദ്ല്യാ നനലിലിത്ഥ ന്ന 1:11:
-Yeah? How close? -Close enough.
൭ ഒലഘ്വാദ ലത - 6ധിഡ്വ ടയ
And they're, you know, not so bad as you say they are.
8:11 1:11:1] ടലി മുയ്ിയ്ലിത്ഥ
Come with me. I got something I want you to see.
യ്‌ ഖര. ൧ഠ൭9 ടടധ്ഡവയ മയി ന്ല്ലത്ധ മ
You know, I'm going to stay here.
ദ്ധ 1ദഡ, ട്വ നല്ഡധഘാഥധഠ്ട്ല്‍
Make sure the floors and countertops are clean before you lock up.
ഉടൂട്ലിക് ന്മ ഠ്ടര്ധനല മട ലട ടലാല്ധസത്ധിവല
Wait. You want me to stay and clean?
പൂം൩. ദ്ധ ന൫0ലിവ ഘാ! 0 നലമ്പാലടിന?
Is that a problem?
൧ഠില്യ് വ ടദ്ധ നടടച്ല്ന
-No. -Good boy. See you tomorrow.
ദ്ധി ധാലി ധന്വാ ത്വ ടെ
We're here.
൭ ൭0 ടാന്വാമ!
Take a good long look, Remy.
“1ല്ഠ൦ധാി-ാലി, സ്പ
Now, this is what happens
വില്‌ ാലില്വ..
when a rat gets a little too comfortable around humans.
൧19 വട ലട 1ലിദ്ധ ടലടടട ഠി ടന്ന നധ്ധട്ദ
The world we live in belongs to the enemy.
ഉല്ല ബബ മ്പ്ിസ്പടഥ
We must live carefully.
ധ൭ നടടല്‍ ബിഠ്ധ്വോ ബാന്ധവ
We look out for our own kind, Remy.
ഗല! ദ്ധണന്൯ ടം, ന
When all is said and done, we're all we've got.
ദി ടന്ധസട ലല ഠില്പാ!! ന, നദ ഡേ 39 1019
No. Dad, I don't believe it. You're telling me that the future is...
150 ൮൭1൨, മവ ലാമ. ൧൭ നലം ല്ല്ഡ മിവ നട ഠ്ലോദന--
Can only be more of this?
൨ബ൭ലാഠില്വുദഠി। ലാ10൨ ഠി ബ്‌?
This is the way things are. You can't change nature.
ബില ഭഠ്ദേ്സമ. ദ്ധ 19൨൦1൦01 ധാ ല്ണ
Change is nature, Dad. The part that we can influence.
ലലെഡാല 3ഠടല൨ ല്ണ, ഖര. ലനാ ൮൭ ന ൧൦1൭൩0
And it starts when we decide.
ഉബാദ ലാല്ധിട ലട ന്ധ ഷ്വാധ്ധടാന
-Where you going? -With luck, forward.
(൭ നന്മ ത്വ നലിലാള്യ്‌? - റ്റ ന്മട॥ാലിപഭ ന്മഠ്ല്യാന
Stop it.
റ സിയ്സുയ
Good morning.
ലനാ
So, the chef, he invited you in for a drink?
പഠി, ധിയാ നട നലൃല്യല്ലിത്ധ ്്ധണന്‌?
That's big.
ധലാസ്നാ
That's big. What did he say?
൮ ലാസ. ൮൭ ഠിദ ൭൭?
What?
വാമ?
What, you can't tell me?
൧്വാട, യവ 1 ഥംാലന്ല്ഡ ലിവ?
Forgive me for intruding on your deep, personal relationship with the chef.
ഗിീീര്ഥ മിവ ഷന നഘാാനണാധ..
Oh, I see how it is.
൭൨, ലിവ ട്വ്ട്നണ ഭദഠ്മ ബ്‌
You get me to teach you a few kitchen tricks
ദ്ധ ധി മിവ ല്യലഭ്ധവാലാലഘ്വാദ 1ലന൩ിഠി। ്ച്വാധ ധിം നനൃമാധസ്ിത്നാഠട..
to dazzle the boss and then you blow past me?
൧൦൩ ഭന്ധാബത്ധ നലഠ്ല്ധഡി്ധ ലിവ?
Wake up. Wake up.
ദ്ഥ. 850൧൩
l thought you were different.
൧ിവ നഉദത്ഥ ത്വ ലാമ
l thought you thought I was different.
൧ിവ ഉത്ഥത്ധ 0 ല്വവാനോടമമ
l thought...
൧ിവ ൫൭൭-
I didn't have to help you!
൧ിവ 1ദിവാല്ധാന്ഡത്ധ!
If l looked out only for myself, I would have let you drown!
പി൭ മവ ബുതയാ3 ഠ10 ലവ, ലിവ 1ല്ധ ൭0 ിലിത്ഥ ത്വ ിണടട!
But...
1ല്വാ!..
l wanted you to succeed. I liked you.
൭1൮ നലിലിത്ധാലുര. ചവ ടിയ ത്വ
My mistake.
൭31൭൨ ൮.
Colette. Wait, wait. Colette!
൦൦൦. സി, നസി. ഠി!
It's over, Little Chef. I can't do it anymore.
9 ഠി ലാലഖിമ്പ, ല്ല റ്‌. ൧ിവ ൭൨ ലലാംില്വാധണ്ിാ
Colette! Wait, wait! Don't motorcycle away.
൦൦൦! സി, ലസി! പ്ു൩ യ 90 ന൦ംടിര! ത്വ
Look, I'm no good with words. I'm no good with food either.
൧ിവ ധി വാട്ട ഠിന ലിത്‌ യദ. ചവ്ധാട ലാല നൂ നലിത്ന്ന
At least not without your help.
ലവഥമവഡവനാസ്ട വഠ്ടവലാഃ സ്ധബിത്ധ
l hate false modesty. It's just another way to lie.
൧ിവ ലാല്‌ നോട നല്ല 0. :151:11:11:11-11- 1:11
-You have talent. -No, but I don't! Really! It's not me.
ദ്ധ 309 0൭1൭
When I added that extra ingredient
8॥ഃ മിവ ലമ്ബാ 0൫൨ സാമ്ന.
instead of following the recipe like you said,
ല്യോട നാഡ ടട വയ ത്വ ല്വ്ത്വോ?
that wasn't me either.
൮ ാഥനാധിത്ഥ മിവ
-What do you mean? -l mean, I wouldn't have done that.
൧്യാട നദിര്ധാ യ്ധ? -ഗിമിദ്ധാവ, മവ ലറത്ബാധഥാല്റ്യ
I would've followed the recipe.
൧ിവ മിത ॥1൮ ടട!
I would've followed your advice.
൧ിവ മിത്൩ി॥വഗാടിന്മത്ധ ടാ ര വ്വ ്ബ്ട
-Because I love your advice. -But...
ലോല മിവ ടര ത്ധ-- നടടിനമധത്ധ - വല്യ?
But I...
1ല്വാ। മവ--
Don't do it.
പുബിച്വഡ്ര്സുമ
Il have a secret. It's sort of disturbing.
൧ിവ മഠ ിടി9. 1൩൭ ൭ നഘാബധ
-l have a... -What? You...
൧൮ ഠി ൮-- - ക്യാമ? !(മ്ധ--
-You have a rash?
- ദ്ധ 09 ബാണ?
No, no, no. I have this... This tiny little...
ദില്ലി കഷ്വ നന്തി ൭ ൭0൦ ബ--
Little...
1(൭ഠ॥--
-A tiny chef who tells me what to do. -A tiny chef?
ലല്‌ ഭം ദ൬൭ ല്ലി ലവ ട്രാ നമിവാധമ.
Yes. Yes. He's...
൭. ൫. ല൭--
-He's up here. -In your brain?
൧3 ഠ। ടടടട്ല്‍ ഥാന ്ലിലിത്ധ?
Why is it so hard to talk to you? Okay. Here we go.
(ന്യാ ടട ടു നല്ലാനയല്ത്വാ ത്്ത്ധ? വം ബ ഠിദ
You inspire me. I'm going to risk it all.
ദ്ധ നന്സാലി മവ നട്രാമടി. ൧ിവ ൫10 ല്വ॥ ടര മട ടട
I'm going to risk looking like the biggest idiot psycho you've ever seen.
൧ിവ നമ ്വ॥ റ്ടിര ഭ0മ10൫ നേന ൦ 919 ഠഠ൦ബയ ത്വ ലാന ഹോ
You want to know why I'm such a fast learner?
ദ്ധ നമവല്സ ന്ഥ മിവ ഠ0ാല്ല്്ച 9൭൩ ലോ?
I'm such a great cook?
ദ്ധ നമവല്ഡ ന്ഥ ലിവ ധി നടി ലാന
Don't laugh! I'm going to show you!
പ്ു൩ിരയ! ചവ ലിത്ഥ ഡബ്ധ്റ്സുമ ശ്വാദഠ്മ ത്ഥ!
No! No!
1 19
-What is it, Ambrister? -Gusteau's.
൧ഠ9 ല്വാമ, ൧്സാലിട്?
-Finally closing, is it? -No.
ചന നലിഗ്ധ്ധാ, ത്ന
-More financial trouble? -No, it's...
[ലിവാബുതയ്്നടടല്ട ക്യാ? - [ടിലിഒ--
Announced a new line of microwave egg rolls?
ഴിലാധന്ധസിത്നാല്ട ലാലി ലഗ്നം ബ്‌
What? What? Spit it out.
൧്യാമ? ക്യാമ? (മദിത്വ
It's come back. It's popular.
19 950 സ്സ. 19 ധി
-l haven't reviewed Gusteau's in years. -No, sir.
൧൮ ഠ്ദ്വി്ലനട 1൭ നഘധിടട ടട്വ വ്വട്ടമ്ധ
My last review condemned it
പടട ലഖ്ന്പിവ നഘധ്ധിലട..
-to the tourist trade. -Yes, sir.
..ഠ ല്‌ ഹാല
l said, "Gusteau has finally found his rightful place in history
ചവ ത്മ, "ദട്ട്ധ ലിമ്പസഭ നല്ലാ! 1ലന്വാമവു ബല്യ ഠ। ഠിന ടല.
"right alongside another equally famous chef,
".ചാലടണട-ടണനട ന്ധ നട 1൩൮൭ ടണട ലശനമ..
"Monsieur Boyardee."
"0705(ഥെ 8ൃഷിഠ൦"
Touché.
ാ്ധാന്നിത്ഥ
That is where I left it. That was my last word.
൧ ടയില്‌ മ്വലാനട്‌. ധിംനിയദിതാ ലന്പിവ
-The last word. -Yes.
(മയ ലമിമ്പ
Then tell me, Ambrister,
ട്ഒഠിാലി്ഡ ലിവ, ൧സ്ബാറിട്ല
how could it be popular?
റ്റി 1വാഠില്വുദഠി। ധി?
The DNA matches, the timing works, everything checks out.
൧1൭൧ ടലാദഠ്, നട ലാട, ടലന്ധസ്ര ലാ!
He is Gusteau's son.
8-111-11]
This can't just happen! The whole thing is a setup!
ബി പന്ഥാ ലലില്ഡ്‌ ല്ധട ബി 31൭൨ ടാഡ ഘ്ല്വ്‌
The boy knows!
്ധാല്ധ്ധ ദ്ധ!
Look at him out there, pretending to be an idiot.
1൦10൭0 19 ഠി ടന. ദല്ാധ്പ്ാധ [3ഠ ൧ഠഠ൦ല്‍
He's toying with my mind like a cat with a ball of... Something.
ഉട നന്ധലന്നല്ബ്ത്ഥ 1നഅ൨൫ ലിവ നേന വനാ ബബോംമ-- ടടട്ധമ്ധ!
-String? -Yes! Playing dumb.
ദയാ? - ൫ ലലാ 0ഠഠ്൦വ്‌
-Taunting me with that rat. -Rat?
ഴിാലലല്‍റലല ലിവ ഠ്്ഇനിവട [ധി - വട?
Yes. He's consorting with it.
പ ൧ലാനമ്ധി ലേ ്സമ!
Deliberately trying to make me think it's important.
ഘോല്വം 0൧൨൭ ലിവറിനു സ്ഥ!
-The rat. -Exactly!
11വട - [ലാട ടലയി॥!
Is the rat important?
൧ഠിട്ഷയനിവട ധ സ്ന?
Of course not! He just wants me to think that it is.
വ ലനസ്ധിം വറ്റ ൧9 ബന 0 ലിവ വിന ബ ാസ്വഥ്!
Oh, I see the theatricality of it.
ചവ ലിന ധ്യ നാ്ദ്ല്യ്സമ
A rat appears on the boy's first night, l order him to kill it.
ലയ ധിവട സ്ഥി 1:11:
And now he wants me to see it everywhere.
0 ടലി ഠി ന്മ൦ല്വ നല്‍ സ൭ 01 നന്ട-നടന്മ
It's here! No, it isn't, it's here!
ഒ ഠി ടലി! നിലേപോധിത്ഥ, ദ ഠി ടലി!
Am I seeing things, am I crazy? Is there a phantom rat or is there not?
ഠ്യ മിവ നല, ഠ്യ മിവ ദ? കാ 0൫൩ ധിവട മ്ദ്ധവഠ്ല്റ
But, oh, no!
ലവ, ൦൩, വഠ്ടിറി
l refuse to be sucked into his little game of...
൧ിവ 1മഗന്ഡ ബാ ഠിന ഗല്നലനമ്സ൭..
Should I be concerned about this? About you?
ദ്ധി മിവ റ്ടദ്ധ നന്മ ബ്‌? ന്ഥ ।ത്ധ?
l can't fire him. He's getting attention.
൧൮ 151൨൦160 0൭൧ ഠി! ൧9 ടട നന്ല്വാ്വാന്മ്ിദ്ല്‍്‌
If fire him now, everyone will wonder why.
പി॥൭ മവ 0൦54 19 ടലിത്ധമയ, ടലന്ധദ ഗു മി നസ ഭഹല്വാ
And the last thing I want is people looking into this.
ലലിത്ഥ ലമിമ്പ പവ നല്ഡ ദല ഗു നനസ്ടടക്നു ബ്‌!
What are you so worried about?
യായ ത്വ ലടദ്ധിത്ഥ ടന
Isn't it good to have the press?
8ധിയബിയ് ാമറ്റട നബ॥॥10 നടഠിദ, ഠ്‌ നന ദ്വട്ഭദ്ധ നബി വല്്ധിധ്ന്മ
Not if they're over his face!
ദിവി ഠി ഡ്യല്സ്!
Gusteau's already has a face, and it's fat and lovable and familiar.
വ്വട്ടദ്ധ 90 ലാഥ ഠി, ടിസ ന്ധി ഠിടദ്ാ! ദ ടടം മ
And it sells burritos! Millions and millions of burritos!
ഉബാദ ന്ധ! ന്ന! 8ല)ഥ്ദുഥ് ലാം!
The deadline passes in three days.
ദ്ധ ഒഥിന ലിത്ഥ ണമ ഠിന 3 0
Then you can fire him whenever he ceases to be valuable
പഠി !യ്ധ 0ഠ1ല൩ 0൭ ഠി 019 919 990 1 ധല്ലമ..
and no one will ever know.
1:11 1:11:1-1:1::1:1-11 11
l was worried about the hair sample you gave me.
ചവ റ്ടമ്ധ നു സം ബാധ ത്ധ ലി 0ദഠ്മിവ.
-l had to send them back to the lab. -Why?
൧ിവ 0൭ മണ്ല ടന്ധിട ഭ നദിന്നമ! - (൭ല്വാ?
Because the first time it came back identified as rodent hair.
മനമ ൭ ഹന്ന ദ അമ്പാടി ഠി ഭനല്വാടടി ടലാമറു! 0ധ്ധ നിവട
-No, no, no. -What?
ലിലി! - ക്യാമ?
Try this. It's better.
ഠ്വോദ ബി. 1 ല്ലിവാദി
Well, because you...
മനമ ത്ധ--
Rat!
11॥1വട!
Disgusting little creatures.
1:11:
! was reminded how fragile it all was.
൧൮ ന്ഥ ക്ഥ 4൦ ഥലക്ഥട ഗ്വാ ടല 0൧
How the world really saw me.
28909ന ഒറ റ്൧൮9 ൧ല0൭൧ ലെ ൧ല0൭ ഒ4൨
And it just kept getting better.
൧൭ ഒ 4ലഡഥട നല്‌ ടന്ന ൧29
Remy!
ലസി
We were afraid you weren't going to, you know, show up.
ശവി മഡാത്ധ ലിന്ഥ സ്ഥലി
-Hey, Remy! How you doing? -You told them?
റല, ദല്പ ധ്യാ നലല? - ദ്ധി ന്നറ
Emile, that's exactly what I said not to do!
സിം, ധില്ന൭ മ്ഡയല്യനാബാധമി
But you know these guys. They're my friends.
ല്വ ദ്വി ന്നി മിവ.
I didn't think you meant them. Look, I'm sorry.
ചവ 1ദിവിന്നത്ധ നലിത്ധാ।ത്ഥ ന്ന ചവ സന്ദ നല്‌
Don't tell me you're sorry, tell them you're sorry.
൩ ത്വാ 9൩ മിവ ത്വ സന്ദ നല്‌, ല്ല്ഡ ന്നലത്ധ സ്മ നല്‌
-ls there a problem over here? -No, there is not.
൧ഠ9 നട്ടില്‍ ഠി ടബ്‌? 1:10 1-1.1:-1
Wait here.
ധ്ാധട്ല്‍
It's locked?
വല്‌?
-Remy, what are you doing in here? -Okay. Emile shows up with...
ലസ, മാദ ൮൬ യവ 0ധമഠ ടബ്‌? - ൦ മ്പി സ്ഥി 9൦--
Okay, I said not to. I told him... He goes and blabs to...
൦ മിവ ൭൭൮9൩. ലവ ഠന്ല്ഡ ഠിദ- - ൧9 ലന്ല്ഡ ാ3ഠ്ട--
Yeah, it's a disaster.
ബര ടദ്ധലാന്ോന്മ
Anyway, they're hungry, the food safe is locked and I need the key.
്യാദ്യധന, ന്നലില്വാല്‌, 06 നദ്ദ ഠി വന ൦ മിവ ഹാലിധിത്ഥ വന൦
-They want you to steal food? -Yes. No! It's...
00 ന്ലിലത്ധ ബോ നല? - ഒ നല ഒ...
It's complicated. It's family. They don't have your ideals.
ബര ഡ്‌. ല്ധുമ. ഗി0വല്ല്രട। 9 ത്വ
Ideals? If Chef Fancy Pants had any ideals,
ഠി? പിയ ധി നടടമ്വലകമ ംന്ട ഠി 1ഠ9൭3..
you think I'd be hawking barbecue over here?
ദ്ധ ടട മവ ലിഖ! ലവ?
Or microwave burritos?
൧്ധ ാധന്നം ലസ്പാഗാ സിന?
Or, Tooth, I say, Tooth Pick'n Chicken?
ക്ട്ധ, മിവ യ്‌, ഖു ലിയ ഠി 1?
About as French as a corn dog!
ലല[മധിട ടലാദദ! ഗന ഠ്‌!
We're inventing new ways to sell out over here.
വി നലഘ്രാട ദേജാ ഥിംനബ്ഡലി!
Will ye be wanting some haggis bites?
൧ഠിടിയ്നിത്ധ ലിഖ നട്ധിത്ഥ നമറഠിട ാലടച്മ 11ന്‌?
I cannot control how they use my image, Remy.
൧ിവ വാരി വാാല്നമന്മ ന്ഥ ധന നല ൭1൮.
-lam dead! -Can you guys shut up?
൧ിവ ൭൨ നമ! - 8ഠ1ല ലിലി ണ്‌!
I've got to think! Word's getting out. If l can't keep them quiet,
൧ിവ ഭന്മവാഹിന്‌ ഒലറ്ജ 1 ലഭലാല. പി॥൭ ടവ വാല ഠില്്ത്ഥ ന്ഥം.
the entire clan's gonna be after me with their mouths open and...
..ടല്ധഡ്‌ വല്ലി ഭ്ച ലിവ 0 ന്ധി 'നേധ്ര
Here it is.
ബി വാധന ഠി
-Oh, this is interesting. Mind if... -Not at all.
൭൨, ബി നടി 8൦1൦0 ലിവ? - [ദപി്ല്ാടനാ
Chef Alfredo Linguini Ask for "What's New"
ധിയാ നട്ടം ധ്‌ ബസരി ബ്ബ "൫൭ ബാബ്‌
Linguini?
ധനധ്ബ്‌?
Chef Linguini: old restaurant's new face
ധിയാ നടിയ: ദ്യ ാബ ഠി ടട
Why would Linguini be filed with your will?
(രറ്വാ നധ്ബ ്ലിത്ഥ ട്രി 9൭൦൩ ധാടിത്ധ?
This used to be my office.
ബി ാനണ്മ്വുദഠി। ല്ലാ മിവ
He's your son?
9 ല്ലില്ല്നിത്ധ?
-l have a son? -How could you not know this?
൧ിവ മഠ9 മലിലില്ലിറ? - റല ന്ധ 0ഠിലലി്വല്ഡ മുബ്‌?
lam a figment of your imagination. You did not know, how could I?
ചവ ബഷ്ല്വന്മര്ംനടാമ്മടിത്ധ!
Well, your son is the rightful owner of this restaurant!
൧ഗട്ലത്ധ 50 ബി॥വു ല്ല 1൭ മട ടട ബി!
No! No! The rat!
ഠ്‌ നിഠ്ച്റ നിവട യ!
-Sorry, chef. -The rat! It's stolen my documents!
ഗി, ധിയാ നടി - വട [വ ൭ ഡോ ഠഠ൦വണടറ ലവ്‌!
-It's getting away! -Hey, Mr. Chef!
9 നലി്ഹിത്ഥ 0!
-You! Get out of my office. -He's not in your office. You are in his.
ദ്ധ! ദ്്ധല ദ്ദ ലാലലാ മവ
Bottoms up, Linguini!
ധ്യ ലട, ൨നാഥ്ബ്‌!
RISING CHEF DECLARED OWNER OF GUSTEAU'S
ധ്വര ള്‍ടചലള്‍്ല്്പശ്റ ചി ॥ടന്ധഥഷശഷ ലല വഡടന്ഥഡ
LINGUINI CANCELS FROZEN FOODS
ലട ഒ ഫധി് ഗിചഡ്വ്ച്പ 85ധ
NEW OWNER NEW GUSTEAU'S
ല്ലി ക്വ പ്വടഥഡ്വ ലക്ഡ
Le Journal GUSTEAU'S RISING STAR
ലച ലല ഷി വ്വട്ഥഡ
-Chef! Chef! -Chef Linguini!
ധിയാ നടി സധിത്ഥ ടട ധിയാ നടിയ!
Your rise has been meteoric, yet you have no formal training.
(ല്ധാഘാന്മ്നത്ധ ടാ ലാട, ദ്വി ന്ധ 1൭ നല്ച്ാദ്‌ധച്നബ്ം്ന!
What is the secret to your genius?
൧്യാടിയ ടിം ശ്വ്വ്ലഭന്മത്ധ?
Secret? You want the truth?
ചിട്ട? ദ്ധ ന്ധ ശ്ധാന്മമ്്‌?
lam Gusteau's son. It's in my blood I guess.
൧൮ ലലല ദ്വട്ഭദ്ധ. 19 ഠി ന ഠ്്മ്വ്വ
But you weren't aware of that fact until very recently.
ല്വ ദ്വ ൮ ട൦ഠ്ച മിത്൩ഘ്വിത് വധ വ്ാലി്ദ്ലാഡാലബ ലി
And it resulted in your taking ownership of this restaurant.
൦൭9 നസ്ുഘാലാത്ത്ധ നാന്സി! ൩ ടട
How did you find out?
റ്റാ യവ ലാഡ്‌?
Well, some part of me just knew.
ലോദി ഠ്0 മിവ നന ൭്ഡ
The Gusteau part?
ഒല്നാിദ ഡട്ടദ്ധ?
-Where do you get your inspiration? -Inspiration has many names.
ഉല നന്മ ത്വ നന്ന്ല്ാ ട്ടി !യ്ധ?
-Mine is named Colette. -What?
ചവ ാധസര ഠ്നനണലിത്ഥ ഠം
Something's stuck in my teeth.
൧ഠ9 ടട ലില്‍യ്‌ ഠി റിവ
Health Inspector.
ട്രാ (4൭51൫൫10
I wish to report a rat infestation.
൧ിവ നലിലില്വാംത്ഥ ടല ധിവട
It's taken over my... Gusteau's restaurant.
൭ 9൭01 നസ ടട൦൫൭0 ൧ ലട വട്ടദ്ധ!
Gusteau's, eh?
ഥേ ദെ?
I can drop by. Let's see. First opening is three months.
൧ിവ ൦1൦1 ടന്ന ॥ഘ.. ലമ്പാധിരാന ലന്നു 3ധി്
It must happen now! It's a gourmet restaurant!
7൭ നടെ ൧ല7൭:ഥ ലേഷ7ഥറ്‌ 7൭ ടലാഒ7 7൭5409൭൨ റാഗ്‌
Monsieur, have the information. If someone cancels, I'll slot you in.
൧ിവ മഠ നമിറ്ധണമഡ. ൭ ടടടിദ്വാദ ാ്മിഷ്ഥ, മിവ ത്ഥ നടടധിറ്ത്ത്ധ
But the rat! You must...
ല്വ ധിവട ഡി! ദ്ധ നടട--
It stole my documents.
1൭ ഡോ വണട ലവ
-It's past opening time. -He should have finished an hour ago.
൧൭൨ നട്ലാ। ടട ഹലമ്പാധിരന - ൧9 ടലാദ്ധസര ലട ടല
Yes, he calls it his tiny chef.
൭, 919 നനനഘാാസഭ സ ല്‌
Not that, dearest. 1 meant you.
ദധി വ, ഖന. ചവ നത്ധഠിത്ത്ധ
-It's him. -Ego?
വധ ഠി - റുഠ?
Is that Ego?
ഠ്യ 9൦?
I can't believe it.
൧ിവ 150 നന്പാലമുയസമ
-You are Monsieur Linguini? -Hello.
൧ഠ9യ ത്വ 70ഠഥട4ഥെ നാഥ്‌?
Pardon me for interrupting your premature celebration,
ഗിീചീര്ഥ മിവ നഘാബാധ ടന്പാഥ് ണന ത്ധ..
but I thought it only fair to give you a sporting chance
901 യവ ടാ 150 ഒഠ॥ ലിത്ഥ ത്വ ടബ്ബ ഥല്ധനാ ഗ്വാ...
as you are new to this game.
നന്ബാത്നത്ധ നടടിപാലബ ഠ്ന ാലന്നലററ ബബ
-Game? -Yes.
ലലെന്നല്നന?
And you've been playing without an opponent.
ഉബിത്ധ ലില്വാന്നട്ഥ 1ഒബ്ാട 5൦൦9 യ
Which is, as you may have guessed, against the rules.
നാ സ്ഥഘനത്ധ ച ഠാല്ം, ന്മ ബോ ഷധത്വ
You're Anton Ego.
ദ്ധി ൧൯൦ ഥാം
You're slow for someone in the fast lane.
ദ്ധ ൩ മ്ബാദ്വ ധി ടടട൦ംാ ൭ നലം 9൭൩ ല്ലോ
And you're thin for someone who likes food.
ഉബിത്ധിവബട ൧9 ടട നായ ട്രി ന്ത
I don't like food. I love it.
൧ിവ 1510 ധിര നമിത. ചവ ന്ന്മ്സു
If 1 don't love it, 1 don't swallow.
വല്യ മിവ 1മനന്ുയിവ്സുയം, ടവ ലറത്ഥ 0
I will return tomorrow night with high expectations.
൧ിവ മത്വാ ന്മിദന ടെ ഠ൭൩ ല്ല!
Pray you don't disappoint me.
8ലഠഠദട൩ധ്വ 1൭ നാഠം്ഷേത്ഥ മിവ
Listen, we hate to be rude, but we're French, and it's dinnertime.
ദ്വി 1൭ ടധിര വനാ ല്ല,
She meant to say, "It's dinnertime and we're French."
൧9 ാല്നമിഭ്ധഠ്‌ നല്യമ്ല്ത്ഥ, "വീട ധിം നിത നമിടന ഠ്ബിന്മ ൦ ലമ്ഥല്ട”
Don't give me that look.
പറ൩ 0 ന മവ ാലറ്വ്യ
You were distracting me in front of the press.
ദ്ധ നഘ്യാദ9്ധ മിവ ഠി ന൯ഠ്ല്യാന നടഠിദ
How am I supposed to concentrate with you yanking on my hair all the time?
റ്റല്നമന്മ മിവ നമ 1ധന്വാധിത്ന ലാമി.
And that's another thing.
ഗഡ ടാഡ ലിത്ഥമു
Your opinion isn't the only one that matters here.
ലെറഠ്ല്യാസയ്ധ ാധിത്ഥ ടബബ-ടദ്ധസര 0൦൯ ഠിട്ബ
Colette knows how to cook, too, you know.
൦ ാഥന ലിസ നനണടടല്ല്ധാദ, ദസ
All right, that's it!
ലിറ, ഡിഡ്വാ!
You take a break, Little Chef.
ദ്ധ ലാലല, ല്ലം ലഘ്‌
I'm not your puppet,
ചവ ാധിത്ഥ 0൦0൭,
and you're not my puppet-controlling guy!
ഠി ത്വ ാധിത്ഥ റ്റു! 0൦ലല്‍൭ ൮
The rat is the cook.
1॥വട ബധിരത നടി
You cool off and get your mind right, Little Chef.
ദ്ധ ഠ്ബോബിത്ഥ 100 ദ്ധ, ല്രിം ല്‌
Ego is coming, and I need to focus!
റും ന്ന, 0 മിവ ലാല്ധ ഠിവട!
You stupid...
ദ്ധ 1ഠഠ൦൩--
Wow. I have never seen that before.
൧ിവ 1മവാലന്മ നം ടലാല്ധന ബി
Yeah, it's like you're his fluffy bunny or something.
൨9, ടടഠ1910-ഠ1911 ദ്ധ ബി ന്ലാധാനോധ്ധസു
I'm sorry, Remy.
ചവ സന്ദ നല്‌
I know there are too many guys.
ചവ 1ദഡ 9 1ലില്ധ മന
- tried to limit... -You know what?
൧൮ ലോദ 0൫൭ഠി൭൦--
It's okay. I've been selfish.
191 ല്വാമ. ചവ ഠട൩൮9ഠ ബ1യ
-You guys hungry? -Are you kidding?
1:11: - ദ്്ധവാല്യധ്ത്ധ ഭര?
All right. Dinner's on me. We'll go after closing time.
ഗിലത൭൧൨ നമിടന മവ ഘാഥന. ധ൭ ത്ഥ ലയി ടലിലാടട നട ധ്യാ
-In fact... -Yeah.
ദല്ല്ഡ ദത ധി ടല്ധ് ധം
Little Chef?
ലില്‍ ല്‌?
This is great, Son. An inside job. l see the appeal.
ബി ഘാല്‌, നല്ലു ൦ ഠ്ടഒണ. ൧ിവ നന്ദിനി!
Little Chef?
ലില്‍ ല്‌!
I thought you went back to the apartment.
ചവ ഉത്ഥത്ധ ലല ാണാടമ്ലാധി
Then when you weren't there, I don't know...
8॥ ദ്ധ 11൭09 ഠി ടാ, മിവ പവ്ല്ഡ--
It didn't seem right to leave things the way that we did, so...
പൂന്വാമിവമി്ലന്മ ധിം ലലത്ഥ ലിത്ഥമ ബി ടലാല്‌ വധ, 9ഠ--
Look, I don't want to fight.
110, മവ ലഗല്വാനേഠ്യ
I've been under a lot of, you know, pressure.
ചവ ാലമഠ്ട ഠി ദധമ്ാബഭത്വലത്ന്ന
A lot has changed in not very much time, you know?
ദസറ ലാബോല ഠിന നടടവയ ട്ഘാതംത്ധ ഖ്ഡ്‌
I'm suddenly a Gusteau.
1109-09 ടവ 150 ദ്വട്ഭദ്ധ
And I got to be a Gusteau or people will be disappointed.
൧0 ടവ ൭൩൫൭൮൭01 ദ്വട്ദ്ധ ദ്ധ ൦ മിതഖ്ലഭഠദേഗമ
It's weird.
1൩൭ ൮ല॥൦
You know, I've never disappointed anyone before,
ദ്ധ ലസ, മവ ലാമ 1ദഠ്ലത്ഥ ടടടില്വാ ടലാല്ധന ബ..
because nobody's ever expected anything of me.
ലോല ഠി ട്ട ലാല നലാിഘ്്വാിത്ന മ്ാദ-ഖ്വാദ ഠ്നാഠ മവ
And the only reason anyone expects anything from me now
൧൦0 ടഡ-ടാഡസയ ടലാലാ 39 ൦00..
is because of you.
നനാന്ലഭ്വിത്ഥ ടട ൦൩ മവ ടല...
l haven't been fair to you.
൧ിവ ൭ ലിലാലില്വ ൦॥ ദ ത്വ
You've never failed me, and I should never forget that.
ദ്ധ 1ദവാലന്മ ഭദ്രത മവ, ഠ്‌ ടവ ലാസ്ഡിധാല്ത്ഥ്ധ
You've been a good friend.
ദ്ധ ടട രഗവ൭ ലി
The most honorable friend a guy could ever ask...
ദമധ൮൭ ദനാ ലിവ ടന്ധട ൦0 നദിഡിത്ന--
What is this?
യാല്‌?
What's going on?
൧്വാ൮൬ ട൦ഠിണാ ലില്വ?
You're stealing food? How could you?
ദ്ധ ന്ഥ നല്ത്ന്‌? ന്നി ത്ധ?
l thought you were my friend! I trusted you!
ചവ നഉത്ഥത്ധിയയറ മിഡ്‌ ൧ിവ ാലാമുതിത്നത്ധ!
Get out! You and all your rat buddies!
ദ്ര്ധ്! ദ്ധ 0 യാനി നിവട യഥ്‌
Don't come back
൦ ടോ 0൭
or I'll treat you how restaurants are supposed to treat pests!
ദ്ധ മിവ ലിത്ലിദത്നത്ധാാല്നടന്മ 951൦0 ധപ ാലാടല്റ്‌
You're right, Dad. Who am I kidding?
ഷുഖ്വാബി. ടില്ാവ൬ മ്വ നല ഗലാഠാഠിത്ന്‌?
We are what we are, and we're rats.
1 മഠ9ല9൩ന്൫, ഠ്൭൦ 109 ദിലി ലിവട
Well, he'll leave soon, and now you know how to get in.
8:11 11:11 11:11: 0] ഒുത്വ ഠഒ0 ല്ഡവാഠാല്നമന്മ ലനം
Steal all you want.
ധില ടണട്ഡ മര
-You're not coming? -I've lost my appetite.
ദ്ധ 130ന്ലിലിഡ്? - കവ 0 ബില ടട
Do you know what you would like this evening, sir?
൧ഠിട്യ്നര്ധ വല്ഡ ട്രാ ൮൬ യവ നല്ഡ നലിന ബ, ഡമ്‌?
Yes, I'd like your heart roasted on a spit.
൭, ലിവ നല്ഡ ലി ദ്ധ റ്ാടിയഷ്വ മ്മടെ ടട നന്നാ
Come in!
[ഗിട്ധിറ്‌
Today's the big day. You should say something to them.
റല ബ നലി൮൭ സ്ഥ. ദ്ധ ാധധിത്ഠ ടട ഠി ന്ഥ
-Like what? -You are the boss. Inspire them.
[ഗി ല്വാമ?
Attention. Attention, everyone.
ലല്ര്ഥിന. ൧ലന്ിന, ടണ്ഡട
Tonight is a big night.
ഗിലിണ ൩ ന്ന സ്ഥ
Appetite is coming, and he's going to have a big ego.
ലീല മിത ഠട്, ൭൦ ഠിദ മിത്ഥ നല്വധസുയി 59൦ ൮൬ ടട
I mean, Ego. He's coming. The critic.
ഗിലിദ്ധാ।വ, 59൦. ൧15 നല. ലലെറ്റിന്ധ
And he's going to order something.
൧൦0 ഠിദ മിര്ബാധമ ടട. ടേടധബ്ഡ
Something from our menu.
ടട നോ നട്ഡേിന്മ
And we'll have to cook it, unless he orders something cold.
ഉബിറ്മ ന്മ നടടല്ലല്‍! [ഴില്ല്ബ്ത്ഥ ഠിദ ാടടറ ടട ടല്ധിം
Just can't leave it alone, can you?
10൦ നലലത വാല ടയ, ൦7
You really shouldn't be here during restaurant hours. It's not safe.
ദ്ധ 15 ടലോദഡസതാനെഠ്ട ഠി ട്‌ി ശവി ടട 10൭. 7 ടടിണ
I'm hungry!
൧ഷിവ പ്ല!
And I don't need the inside food to be happy.
2-11-11 11111111: ധിധാന്േധട ൫൭1
The key, my friend, is to not be picky.
ധ്യ, യധാബി്വ, 1: :11116111:111 1-1]
-Observe. -No, wait!
ലലഷിത്വ - 191, നസി!
-Oh, no! No, no! What do we do? -I'll go get Dad.
൨,൯00 ന്ദ ൧്യാട ന നലിവാ്ധമന
You might think you are a chef but you are still only a rat.
ദ്ധ സ്ധഥഘാന൬൩ നാ ധ്വ മഠ്ടില ഡി നടടം..
Sure he took away a star last time he reviewed this place.
ഴി ഠി ദ ലാല ടദ്ധ ന്നാ യി ൩0 ഗദ നല്്രിടട ന്മ
Sure it probably killed... Dad.
ഴി സ്ധനഘാന്൩സദ ൭ നനമ്പധന്ധ വട ഖര
-This is very bad juju right here. -But I'll say one thing...
ബ്‌ നണനാ ടന്മാ ഡി ട്ലി - [ല്യി മിവ ലിഖ ത്ലിത്ഥ ടവ വാലിത്വ--
-Ego is here. -Ego? He is here?
റും ൭൨ ടാന്വാദി - റുഠ? ൧1 ൭൨ ടന്വാല്‌?
Anton Ego is just another customer. Let's cook!
൧൯൦൫ ലാം ബഭ്ലി ടല 0ല്‍ഘാ0൩. [ഗീ നനടടമിറ
Yeah! Let's...
ച ഗീ്--
So I have in mind a simple arrangement.
ചവ നന്യാധസരി 1000൩൭ സ്വാ ഠി നനആ്൩
You will create for me a new line of Chef Skinner frozen foods.
ദ്ധ മിത നല്ലാ ിയ്ന നലിത്ന്ന ലവ ്ധിര്ഥാ നടടലറന്നല ധന്ധംല്വ
And I, in return, will not kill you.
൧0 3൮, ടലാദാദ 31950, 1 11111111
Au revoir, rat!
ലന 510൨, നിവട!
Do you know what you would like this evening, sir?
൧ഠിടിയ്നത്ധ ല്ഡ ല്യാവയത്ധനല്ഡ നടിന വി, ഡന്‌?
Yes, I think I do.
൭, ലിവ ടാ ലിവ ല്ഡ
After reading a lot of overheated puffery about your new cook,
ടലില്ാടട നലമ്പാടഠേ ബസി ലാലലിയത്വാലറ നലഖമ്വാദ്ധ നു ധരാ നടടമി്റാബത്ഖ..
you know what I'm craving?
ന്ധ 1്ഡ ഖ്വാ൮൭ വ നല്ഡ?
A little perspective.
॥ലാലദ്വാലസ്‌
That's it. I'd like some fresh, clear, well seasoned perspective.
വ ടല. ൧൨ നല്ഡ വാലസ്‌ ടല, ലട, ഠ്വാല്മടലിത്ഥ ഠോ
Can you suggest a good wine to go with that?
8ഠില൩ത്ധ ോ്യിക്ന ഡ്ബ വാലി 1 ഠിഠുഠ്ഘത്ഥ ബബ?
-With what, sir? -Perspective. Fresh out, I take it?
ഉറ്റ ല്വാാ, ഡന്‌?
lam...
൧ിവ--
Very well. Since you're all out of perspective
ലിറ. 'ഗീനമറഠ്ഘത്ലിത്ധ ടന്ധദ ലാ ഠി ഡല വാല്ട്വാല്‍വ്‌..
and no one else seems to have it in this bloody town,
൩ 1ഠ9 ട്വ നല്പി॥ന്പര ഠി ഠം ബ..
I'll make you a deal.
൭1൮ ദിത്ബാധമ്‌ ടാ ലുദവിദ് ബ്ബിത്ധ
You provide the food, I'll provide the perspective.
ദ്വ ടടഠിദിത്വ നല, ടവ ദിത്ഥ ടിലിത്ബ്ാല്ട്വാല്‍വ്‌
Which would go nicely with a bottle of Cheval Blanc 1947.
0 ടടടധല ന ടലാഠ൦। ൨0൫൭൧൮ ലിദം 1947
I'm afraid I...
൧ിവ ടട മിവ--
Your dinner selection?
ലല നല്ത്ഥ ന്മിദണത്ധ?
Tell your Chef Linguini that 1 want whatever he dares to serve me.
ദലന്ല്ഡ ധി നടടച്നാധ്ത്‌..
Tell him to hit me with his best shot.
ദലന്ല്ഡ ഠി ധി്ലാലിത്ഥ ട്വ ൫൭ട॥ നാലിനു
I will have whatever he is having.
൧ിവ ന്യാ ൮൭ ഠിദ ൫
-So, we have given up. -Why do you say that?
പഠി, ൩൩ ഠ്ദ്വാന്ോധ്ധട ഒട്‌? - (ദറല്വാധ്ധ യി ാല്ഡ?
We are in a cage inside the car trunk
ധാ ഠിന ടത ഠി സ്വാം ഭഷഖദ
awaiting a future in frozen food products.
ഴില്ഡഘാധ നട ഠില്ാമന 00ഠഠ്ധി ന്ത ാലവ
No, I'm the one in a cage. I've given up.
1150 മിവ ൮൬ ലാട ഠിന ടയ. ൧ിവ ൮൬൭ ൧0 ണബധഡട മട
You are free.
ദ്്ധാലാടട
lam only as free as you imagine me to be.
൧ിവ സഭ ലാലാമട ടലാപസ ൮൬൭ ത്വ വന്യത മിവലാലാടട
As you are.
ലോലി !ധ്വ
Oh, please. I'm sick of pretending. I pretend to be a rat for my father.
൭൨, 1൦19൨.
I pretend to be a human through Linguini.
൧ിവ ലാലാഥ്മാധ്മദഠി। നധ്ധട്ദ നലല്ധി ന്‌്‌
I pretend you exist so l have someone to talk to!
൧ിവലാലാഥ്മാഥ്മത്ധ ഖ്്്ധഠ ട്വ ടവ 9 രഡലാലഥലിയ്വ!
You only tell me stuff I already know!
ദ്ധ ഡബേന്ാല്്ഡ ല്വ ാലിത്തമവയ ടവ ൩ ല്ഡി!
I know who I am! Why do I need you to tell me?
൧ിവ ദസ ടില്വാദ മിവ! (൭റ്വാധ്ധ ന ലാല്ല്ഡ ലവ?
Why do I need to pretend?
(ന്യാ മിവ ല്ധ ാധത്പ്ാധ്തമ്‌?
But you don't, Remy.
വല്യ ദ്വ ദ്വാനാധാധഥട, സ്പ
You never did.
ദ്ധ ദിവാലി
No. My other left!
ധി, ടലാലമസ൮൭ ടട !!
Dad? Dad, I'm in here!
ചുന ചയ, ലിവ മഠ ഠി ടബ്‌!
I'm inside the trunk! What the...
ചവ ലാലമഠ്ട ഠി സ്വാം! കാ ൮൬--?
Dad!
തി!
-Hey, little brother! -Emile!
01, ഒഠി॥0 - സില്‍!
Il love you guys!
1-11-11 11:11
Where are you going?
൭ നന്മ ൭ നാല്‌?
Back to the restaurant. They'll fail without me.
(മ്പാഃ!! ൭ ൭൦90. 00 ലിത്ഥ 9൭ ബ്ദ മിവ
-Why do you care? -Because I'm a cook!
(ദറല്വാ യവ ട്വ! - ലാലാ മവ ടല ഡിത്നാ നടടല്റ്‌
It's your recipe.
9 ടട! ദ്വ.
How can you not know your own recipe?
റ്റി യവ ഠി ലി്നല്ഡ ടട !യ്ധ ടാ?
I didn't write it down. It just came to me.
൧ിവ 150 നന്ധിടസര. 19 ഠി "ബട ഠാഠ്ദ മിവ
Then make it come to you again. Because we can't serve this!
പ്ഒഠി ധിം ക്നാ ത്വ ടന്ധിട. ലോല ൩൭ വാം വാ്ഘത്ല ല്‍
Where's my order?
[ഗന ടട ട്വ?
Can't we serve something else? Something I didn't invent?
1 ധാംിലവ്ഷ്വന്ദ ബിഘോത്ഥ ടട ഴു ലന ടടട്ധമ്ധവ൭ ലിവ ലം ല്ല?
They're ordering this.
ഗ്0ധാ൦ടന ബി
Make them order something else. Tell them we're all out.
ദ്ധ ന്നലാടടന ടട 1൩. (മറ 1 റല്ിട
We cannot be out. We just opened.
൭ പ്വാംിലവത്ട നല്ി്ട? ഗ്വാ ധ്രു
l have another idea. What if we serve them what they order!
൧൮ ഠി 1൭3 1൭൩. ൧൭൫൭൭ ൯൩൭ വഠ്ഘാത്ഥ ന്ഥില്വാവയ ന്ന്ലാടമല്‍്‌
We'll make it. Just tell us what you did.
ബി മഖ നന്സ്ധസഭ. 8ല്ല്ഡ ടല്യമ യി മാദ ൮൬ യവ ഠവല
I don't know what I did.
൧ിവ ദിവസ ലാവ മവ ഠ്ദ്നവാധമ
We need to tell the customers something.
ധ൭൭൫൭ ൧ലന്ല്ഡ ലാല ടട
Then tell them... Tell them...
ദംന്ല്ഡ ന്ന. 8ല്ല്ഡ ന്ന.
-Don't do it. -Remy. Remy.
പുബിച്വഡ്ര്സുമ
Don't! Stop! They'll see you. Stop.
പ൩ ദം! [0 ലിത്ഥ നന്വാല്ലത്വ. ദല
We're not talking about me. We're talking about what to do right...
ധവാധിത്ബാലലിത്വാ ലാട! ലവ. ഗദ ലിത്വാ 1 മല ൮൬ ലടറ്ധ ഠധമ്ലാബി--
Rats!
11॥1വട!
-Remy! -Get my knife.
ലസി - മ്പ! ലിടമ്ധ മിവ
Don't touch him!
ടല ടസ്ധഥ ഠിം
Thanks for coming back, Little Chef.
ലിന ൭ട ഘടന ഭമ്പാടി॥, ലില്‍ ല്‌
I know this sounds insane, but...
൧ിവ 1മ്ഡവാധസസ്സമ ദ ്വ--
Well, the truth sounds insane sometimes.
ഠ്യ ഭ്വാമന്മലമ ന്നാ ഭാഭ ദ
But that doesn't mean it's not the truth.
ല്വധ 1 ധാലന്നലിഭ്ധഠ ദ മവാന്ല
And the truth is, I have no talent at all.
൧0 ടലാനമസ്ൂഭ, ടവ ്വലാനാലത്ടഥനാ
But this rat, he's the one behind these recipes.
വല്യ ധിവട ബ, ദില ം൦ുഠി ലപ്യ്നാ ടട01-ടടില ല്‍
He's the cook. The real cook. He's been hiding under my toque.
൧1൭൨ ഡിത്നാ നടടലം ധിയാ നട ലാല്ല
He's been controlling my actions.
൧9൮൬൭ നട്ടി ടാലി 10ഠ്ലിത്ഥ ടവ
He's the reason I can cook the food that's exciting everyone.
ഥ॥ദല്വവാസുഘാലാ മിവ ലാല നനമടമി നമിത.
The reason Ego is outside that door.
ലോല്വ ഭറ്വാ റും ലലമഠ്ട ഠി ടി]
You've been giving me credit for his gift.
ദ്ധ 1൭0 നന്സാലിത്ഥ മിവ നട ഷമ ല്ത്സര
I know it's hard to believe.
൧ിവ ഡാ ടിയ ലാമ.
But, hey, you believed I could cook, right?
റല, യവ 0 ടവല്‍ നടനടടല്ലത്ന?
Look, this works. It's crazy, but it works.
ലി, ബ്‌ധാടണ്ടട॥ ബസ 9൭ ഒല ാലന്മട॥
We can be the greatest restaurant in Paris,
ധവാഠില്വുദഠി! 651090 ൭0ലാ൭ ഠി ൧ട്ലിട,
and this rat, this brilliant Little Chef, can lead us there.
ഠി നിവട ബി, ല്വം ഘാല്‌, ൮൬ 001൦൩ നലന്പാദ്ഡ ൫91൪ ടന
What do you say? You with me?
൧്വാ യ്ത? ദ്ധ മവ?
Dad.
ഷുത്വ
Dad, I don't know what to say.
൧൮൭1൨, ലവ ലമ്ഡ ലാ നലലത
Il was wrong about your friend and about you.
൧൭1൨ ടല 0 രല ത്വ ദ്ദബാടട! ത്വ
I don't want you to think I'm choosing this over family.
ചവ 1മന്ഡ മര ലിവ ലിന ൩ ണം ദ്ധ
I can't choose between two halves of myself.
൧ിവ ദവാ 010 റവ ദനാ ഠ്നിവ ടാ
I'm not talking about cooking. I'm talking about guts.
ഷുഖ്്വാധിത്ലാനലത്വാ 7 നനടടമി ഷുഖ്വാലത്വാ മാ ദ്ധ
This really means that much to you?
ബി ടാ ലന്നലിന്മ ാധമ്ധത്ധ?
We're not cooks, but we are family.
ധവാധിത്ഥ ഡി നടടല്പല്വ! ന്ദ ദ ിശ്ധു
You tell us what to do, and we'll get it done.
ദ്ധവാല്മ്ഡതസി ല്യാ നമധ്ധല, 0 യി പ്ത്ഥ ടില്ലിഖ്സ
-Stop that health inspector. -Delta Team, go, go, go, go!
റസ്ിത്ഥ നടാലി ഭടിഘ്ബ്ഡ
The rest of you stay and help Remy.
നാ ലനാ ണിം ൯
Team three will be handling fish. Team four, roasted items.
ഉദുടധിത്ഥ വറ ിയ്ഥ ധബടിത്ഥ ത്വ ഉദുടധിത്ഥ 4: നന്മ
Team five, grill. Team six, sauces. Get to your stations. Let's go, go, go!
ഉദുടധിയ്ഥ 5: നാഠ0ി. ടടധിത്ഥ 6: ട൦ംട
Those handling food will walk on two legs.
0൮൮ നഘധബടിത്ഥ നല്ക ല്ത്ഥ 0ല)ദ്ന മടടെ ദ്ധ വറി
We need someone to wait tables.
ധ൭ാലിധിത്ന ടട 1ഡാധ നലഃ
I'm sorry for any delay, but we're a little short tonight.
ഗി മട ദിശ ബ, ലവ ബി 1111-11 11:111:11:111111
Please, take all of the time you need.
൧ാലടിപ്യ്ഥ, മ്പ ടാല്ട നട റു ത്വ ഹലിധിത്ഥ
He came in late one more time and all of a sudden he...
8-111-11 11:11 :11] 19-09 ഠ19--
Make sure that steak is nice and tenderized.
ഉടൂട്ലിക് ബില്ധ ടടഠ്ല്യാ ന ില്പാഥ്‌
Work it. Stick and move. Stick and move.
പടദ്മിര്സ൭. 1൭ ഠി ഥി 1൦൭ ൭൭ ഥി
Easy with that sole meuniére. Less salt. More butter.
90-0൭ 90 ടട നടഥ്ബ്ലെ ഡ. ധാത്ഥ 9൭൬൩. ൨ലാിവത്ഥ നലഃ
Only use the mimolette cheese.
൨൩൭ റാ ഷ്യ സ്നംിങ്ല
Whoa! Compose the salad like you were painting a picture.
വ്യാ ടിദഠി നേന ത്൨ ടട നലധിഠട ടട റു്സാല
Not too much vinaigrette on that salade composée.
പ്റ്൩്ല്ധാബസര്ഡലാഭ 03ഠി ടമിദഠില ഗഠന്വാട൦
Don't let that beurre blanc separate. Keep whisking.
റ്ബ്ലിത്ാലേട ധിം ബട. ബട നന്ധിഡ്സര
Gently poach the scallops. Taste check. Spoons down.
ലില്ലി ബ്ലിശയ്വ്ടയ ലലാം മട. വസബിത്ഥ ടവ
Good. Too much salt. Good.
ദമറ്റ്ട. "ലില്ധ ാബസരിറുല്ന. 8്ധട
Don't boil the consommé, it'll toughen the pheasant. Emile!
൩൦ ഠിഠ്ിബ്ത്ഥ ഗടംന്നട, ഒ മിത്ഥ നാലടി വല ധാദരട. ബില!
Colette, wait! Colette.
ഠിം, ലസി! ഠിം
-You came back. Colette... -Don't say a word.
ദ്ധ ഠാ 09൦ ഠ൦1ങ൦-- - പ൦ ദ്ലിത്വാ ടലാമ്മ ലാ.
If l think about it, I might change my mind.
പിര പവ നിനിര്സ്സമ, ട്വ സ്ഥാന ധാല്വിന്ത്ഥ
Just tell me what the rat wants to cook.
ഡ്ധന്വാല്ല്ഡ ലിവ ലായ നിവടയ നമ നട
Ratatouille? It's a peasant dish.
ഖാലി? ബര ബ്ദ ല്ലി
Are you sure you want to serve this to Ego?
൧ഠിടിയ്നത്ധ ഗദ ത്വ നലബിഘോത്ഥ ബി നഠ 59൦?
What? I am making ratatouille. Well, how would you prepare it?
യാമ? ൧൮൮൬൭ നണട മഖ്ദി റ്റി !യ്വ ലിത്ഥ ഠ്യ?
Ratatouille? They must be joking.
ഖാലി? [ള്‍്0ിനലസ്ധാനയധഥ്ത്ധ
No, it can't be.
ഠ്‌ 1 സ്ധ്്ന ടില്വാ ൮൬ നടില്ല വധ?
I can't remember the last time
1:11
l asked a waiter to give my compliments to the chef.
111011 111-11111॥:1111 ൦] വധി നടടട
And now I find myself in the extraordinary position
ഉ ടിനു മവ ദലാല്‍ മിവ ലാലമഠ്ട ഠി ഭാധാധിത്ന൮യ൭ ഡല ഒട.
of having my waiter be the chef.
൧19 ലാല മവ 31൭൨ ല്‌
Thanks, but I'm just your waiter tonight.
ലണ തടി ്വി മവ ബഭ്്ല ഗദ ധ്ധ ന്മിദണ ബി
Then who do I thank for the meal?
പഠി 09ഠി9 ടിദ്വാദ മവ ന0ഡാല്വോത്വ ലന യടി ഥി നലിത്്്ധ?
Excuse me a minute.
ഗിഠചീര്ഥ മിവ ടലഷ്ല്വാ
You must be the chef.
ദ്ധ ന്ധ ഡിത്നാ നടടല്ല്ധ പിതത്ധ നല്ധധന്വാ ഡി നടടല്ം,
If you wish to meet the chef, you must wait until all other customer have gone.
ത്വ നടട॥ ഡനാധ ടാ സ്പ 06 ഠ്ദ്വാഃ॥ം
So be it.
പഠി മവ ലിത്ല ന
At first, Ego thinks it's a joke.
൧ഒ9റ്9 നഥഥ൭, £റഠ ഥഗറുല്ക്റഥ 7൭ 594൧റെ൭'൪
But as Linguini explains, Ego's smile disappears.
7ഒഥ൧ (ഭഥല൪൭ ൧൧00൧ നഖ൮(൭ഒട4൭൧ഥ൧)൭, ട്ലൃഡ്ണക ൧9൦ 777൭൧റ്റ
He doesn't react beyond asking an occasional question.
൧9 4ഒ ഥലഗറ്ടഥഖടട ടല'ഒഥ റ്ഥാഠ്‌ 2ല൭൧)൭ ടഠഒ(ഒഥ ടലഷ-ടല്ഷഒ
And when the story is done, Ego stands, thanks us for the meal...
൧ഒ൦ഥ 249 ല്‌ ! ലട, 20൦0 ൧2൭൧൮൧,
Thank you for the meal.
ലണ തടി മട നലിത്നന ത്വ
..and leaves without another word.
.. റ ലസ്സ്‌ 4൭൧0൭ ലാട'ഒ7 ലട !൭07
The following day his review appears.
൧7 ഗാല ധ്‌ നഗ
In many ways, the work of a critic is easy.
൧൩ ൧2൭൧൭ ൧൭൦൭, ഗ്ു൭5 ൧ലറ്ഗ്ധ്‌ ഒഠ്ട൭ഒ൦ 797
We risk very little, yet enjoy a position over those
൭൩ (ഒററുററഥറ 757൭ )൭ ടെറ! (ഥ്‌,
who offer up their work and their selves to our judgment.
൭ നലടടഥക്ഥ ൭ നഗ വ്ഥ്‌ 77 ശെല (ക
We thrive on negative criticism, which is fun to write and to read.
ഗ്ട ഗ്ര ഗ്ധഥ ഗ്ന 9 ടല൦ഠ000% വട റ്൭റ ഗ്ഥഒ൦൭െ
But the bitter truth we critics must face is that in the grand scheme of things,
7ഒഥ൧ 0൭ഗ്൪൭ ഗ്‌ 9 ൭൩ ൧റെറ്ഗ്ധ്ലഥാടദ ഗഒറ്ഒ൧..
the average piece of junk is probably more meaningful
..2ലെറ്ട 49 ഗഗ) ൧ഒടട സനഥ്റ്ഗ 4൧൧0 ൧ല൬ന൭ഗഒ..
than our criticism designating it so.
.. വാറ്‌ (ഗ്ധക്ഥ)ഴ :ഗ്ട 2മ്ക്ഥ
But there are times when a critic truly risks something
7ഒ൧! ഒറ്9 1൭റ൧)൭ ൧0 ാറെറ്റഗ്ധ്‌.
and that is in the discovery and defense of the new.
.. റ 74ധ൦ റല റ്ഒഥ ല്ല 4ലഗദറ്ദാ 0 ൧൭൧
The world is often unkind to new talent, new creations.
ഗഥഗ്ഒ ടലഒഗഥുഭ 4൭൧൦5൭ 2൭൧ ലനദറ്മ്ഥ ൧2൭! ൧൭൧൧, ഥാഒറ ഒ
The new needs friends.
൭൧൮ ൧2൭ഡഥഥാഗെധക്റ കഥക
Last night, ! experienced something new,
ഗഒഒ൭ന !9൨്‌ ഒ൭4൧ നലെററ൭൭൩ ടേഥദ്ഥ ഗാഡ
an extraordinary meal from a singularly unexpected source.
൧ഠഒഥറുണറ !4൧൭ ൧95൭ ന്ഥ 59 5൧൩൧ല7 9 ൭ വഥറകക്ഥ
To say that both the meal and its maker
ഗ്ര്ധനമെറ്റട്ഒക്റ (൭ഠ്ഥ-റ്ഥഒ ഗറ്ഥറ്റഥ റ്ഒഥ ഥലഥ്ഥ4ഒഥ)൭..
have challenged my preconceptions about fine cooking
..4ഖലഒ7 7൦൦൧൭7 ൧79-ഒ൭റ്റററദ്ാറെ ഒ:൧ 0 സനടദക്ഥുഴ ൧7.
is a gross understatement.
..ഒറ്൭4൭7 (കഥൃ൭(ഒഒഥ ൬ 4ല്ഥ്‌
They have rocked me to my core.
എഴന്ല്ല നറെറ്ററുറ്റക്റ ഒഗ ട്ലാഗറററട (ഭ വ്‌
In the past, 1 have made no secret of my disdain
൧൭റ്9 ൩൭.൭ 4ലാ൭.5 ഒ൧ (ഒ നബെസാഥ്ശ്ക..
for Chef Gusteau's famous motto, "Anyone can cook."
..4ഖലഗദഠ്ദാ 77ഠഠ !ഒ്കഥഒ! ൭56൭൭൧, "൭ഒ൭4ഒ൭൧൭ 204൭7 7 ലനടടറ്‌
But I realize only now do truly understand what he meant.
7ഒ൧! ൭൧ ടഠറ്൭7 07൧൭ ലഷ്‌ ഒ൨൧ ലാമ 7ഒഗ0ഒന ഒട നഗ്ന
Not everyone can become a great artist,
൧ഥക്റ ടെ 20൭൧ (ഒ൨്‌ ൭൪5 19 ലാട.
but a great artist can come from anywhere.
4ല്൭ാ7 ഒന്‌) ഗലാഒ! ൧0ലാ റ്9ഒഥറ ൨൦ നറ ൭൭
It is difficult to imagine more humble origins
കഥ ശ്ടയക്ഥറ്ക്ഥ ഒട൭ ൧5൧) 4൧൧0 ഗലറ്ദഗ ന്൦്‌..
than those of the genius now cooking at Gusteau's,
.. വാറ്‌ സ്ലുഴ ൧൧൫൭൮൬ റെ നണട ധ്‌ ഥേട4ഒഒ൧൭..
who is, in this critic's opinion,
..1, ൧ഒറ്9 ൧ററ്മ്ഥട! ഗ്ധഥ..
nothing less than the finest chef in France.
..൭ലഡഗഥറ ഗലാദ! ഥലാടറ്ററ്റ ഗരഥറ ന൭൭5൭ലാ൭ ധ്‌ ൧ലക്ഥധ്ട
! will be returning to Gusteau's soon, hungry for more.
൧൮ ഒ൭രഥ (൩൧൭൧7 (൭ ഥേട4ഒഒ൧5 79% 4൭നഒ (ഒ൭൮, (ഒ൧൭ ൭൮
It was a great night. The happiest of my life.
൫ ന ഖഒന 9 ലാട. 0 ൧൭൧റ നെറ്റു ദന വ്‌വ്ഥ്ഥധ
But the only thing predictable about life is its unpredictability.
7ഒ൧! ഒ ഥല്ഷട ൭ ൧ഠല റ്7ഒ൦0൭ 10 ഗ7റ്൧൧ 4൭4൭7 )0 4൭ ധ്ഠ% സ്ന ഒ
Well, we had to let Skinner and the health inspector loose,
൭൩ (൧൧൭(൭൭ 2ഒഥ്ക്ഥ ഗല” റ്ഒഥ ൧൭൭൧ല്‍ (൭൭5.൧0൭[ഒ൭൧ഥ 4ഖ്ാ൭൭..
and of course they ratted us out.
..റ്൭ഥ, റല 44, ന7വഗഗടെ ൭
The food didn't matter.
൧൭5ഒ ന൭ഭഥ൭ 4൭ ഥെ.
Once it got out there were rats in the kitchen,
2879 ൧ലസ്ട൭ ഒഠ്ട 7:ഡ5 വ്‌ ന്ന റ്ട്വാഥ്‌..
oh, man, the restaurant was closed.
7൭50൭൧ 70 വ്ഗ്ഥ
Ego lost his job and his credibility.
റും വിദ ഭ൮ദ ഠ്ബനം॥॥സു൭
But don't feel too bad for him.
ലവ മവ ലട ടിന
He's doing very well as a small business investor.
൧9 ലുദ്ധവമ ടലാമറുദ ാല്ലാധ ഹിമ ൭൦
-He seems very happy. -How do you know?
ഉട ടാനാമ്‌ സ്പ ഗ്ന ധ്ധവല്ഡ?
Got to go. Dinner rush.
(൭0൫൭ ലാല. 'മിഡ ടടട്നലിത്ഥ ന്ന
You know how he likes it.
ദ്ധ 1്ഡവാഠാല്നമന്മ ഠിദ ധ്യ
Can I interest you in a dessert this evening?
ദ്ധ നമാ സ്ധി്ഥ നമി ബ്‌?
-Don't you always? -Which one would you like?
1150൭0 ടടില്ധസരലാല്ഡ? - ന നമ്മ ടധത്ധ നല്ഡ?
Surprise me.
്്ധിത്ഥ ടവ
Can I interest you in a dessert this evening?
ദ്ധ നമാ സ്ധി്ഥ നമി ബ്‌? നാ നന്മ ടബ്ധ?
Hey, believe me, that story gets better when I tell it, okay?
ലലെ മവമില, റ്ടല0 ബ്‌ ടനടിന്പാട॥ 9 മിവ ല്ലി, ന
Come on. Bring some food over here, we're starving!
ല്ലോ 8 നലിത്നിഭ ടബ്‌, യി ഠ്ട്നില്യാ!